记住 别缩着肩
Now remember, keep your shoulders back.
好的 胳膊搂着你弟弟
Okay, put your arm around your brother. That's it.
就这样 对 呼吸
That's it. Right, and breathe in.
对了 再来一张
Okay, one more.
死
亡
诗
社
好了 再说一遍
Now, just to review
一直走到校长面前
you're going to follow along the procession until you get to the headmaster.
然后他会叫你把孩子们手里的蜡烛点燃
At that point, he will indicate to you to light the candles of the boys.
好了 孩子们 准备吧
All right, boys, let's settle down.
举旗
Banners up!
女士们 先生们 孩子们...
Ladies and gentlemen, boys...
智慧之光
the Light of Knowledge.
一百年前 1859年
One hundred years ago, in 1859
四十一个孩子坐在这里
41 boys sat in this room...
被问到了同样的问题
and were asked the same question...
每个新学期开始都会问到的问题
that now greets you at the start of each semester.
各位 我们四大支柱是什么
Gentlemen, what are the Four Pillars?
传统 荣誉 纪律 优秀
Tradition. Honour. Discipline. Excellence.
建校第一年
In her first year
本校毕业了五位学生
Welton Academy graduated five students.
去年 毕业生是五十一人
Last year we graduated 51.
其中百分之七十五以上
And more than 75 percent of those...
进了名牌大学
went on to the Ivy League.
这种成就来源于
This... This kind of accomplishment is the result...
我们所孜孜遵循的上述教学原则
of fervent dedication to the principles taught here.
这是各位家长愿意把孩子们送到这儿来的原因
This is why you parents have been sending us your sons.
也是本校成为全美最优秀的预备学校的原因
This is why we are the best preparatory school in the United States.
大家知道
As you know
英语系的波希尔斯先生上学期光荣退休了
our beloved Mr Portius of the English Department retired last term.
本学期接替他的将是约翰・基丁先生
You will have the opportunity later to meet his replacement, Mr John Keating,
也是本校的优秀毕业生之一
himself an honours graduate of this school.
过去的几年中 他一直...
And who, for the past several years, has been teaching...
在享有盛誉的伦敦切斯特中学任教
at the highly regarded Chester School in London.
理查德 你忘记了你的包
Richard, you forgot your bag!
约翰 最近还好吗
Hi, Johnny! Hey, how you doin'?
不用担心 我拿到了你的房间安排
Don't worry. I got your room assignment.
他们吃饭的地方没有改呀
They haven't moved the dining area.
谢谢你光临
Glad you could come by.
- 仪式很精彩 一如既往 诺兰博士  - 很久不见了
- Thrilling ceremony, as usual, Dr Nolan.  - You've been away too long.
- 你好 诺兰博士  - 很高兴你们能回来
- Hello, Dr Nolan.  - Good to have you back.
- 这是我们最小的儿子托德  - 安德森
- This is our youngest, Todd.  - Mr Anderson.
你的前途很大 年轻人 令兄是我们最出色的学生之一
You have some big shoes to fill. Your brother was one of our finest.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 仪式很精彩  - 谢谢 很高兴你能喜欢
- Lovely ceremony.  - Thank you. Glad you liked it.
- 盖尔  - 汤姆
- Gale.  - Tom.
- 很高兴又见到你  - 你好 诺兰先生
- Good to see you again.  - Hello, Mr Nolan.
- 尼尔 希望你今年能取得好成绩  - 谢谢
- We expect great things from you this year.  - Thank you, sir.
他不会让我们失望的 对吧 尼尔
Well, he won't disappoint us. Right, Neil?
我会努力的
I'll do my best, sir.
过来 孩子
Hey, come on, son.
- 振作些  - 好的
- Chin up.  - Okay.
- 别哭  - 振作些
- No tears now.  - Chin up.
- 我不想来这儿  - 亲爱的 我爱你
- I don't want to go here.  - Honey, I love you.
- 我送你过去  - 好了 好了 好好学习
- I'll walk you over.  - You be a good boy. Do your lessons.
嘿 听说我们同宿舍
Hey! I hear we're gonna be roommates.
- 我叫尼尔・佩里  - 我叫托德・安德森
- I'm Neil Perry.  - I'm Todd Anderson.
干嘛换到这儿上学
Why'd you leave Balincrest?
我哥就来的这儿
My brother went here.
就是那个安德森
Oh, so you're that Anderson.
- 这是治他鼻窦炎的  - 是的 我知道
- This is for his sinuses.  - Yes. I see.
如果他咽不下去就给他吃点这个
Oh, and if he can't swallow, you give him one of these.
如果他呼吸困难 可以给他吃点这个
And if he has trouble breathing, you can give him some of those.
- 记得带喷雾器了吗  - 带了 放在宿舍了
- Did you remember your vaporizer?  - Yes, I put it in my room.
- 嘿 你好吗 尼尔  - 你好
- Hey, how's it going, Neil?  - Hey, Knox.
尼尔 今晚学习小组
Neil, study group tonight?
- 嗯 当然  - 跟以前一样
- Yeah, sure.  - Business as usual, huh?
嘿 听说你有了个新室友 像个木瓜一样
Hey, I heard you got the new kid. Looks like a stiff!
哎哟
Oops.
听我说 别理会他
Listen, don't mind Cameron.
他呢 狗嘴吐不出象牙 明白我的意思吗
He was born with his foot in his mouth. You know what I mean?
听人说你上暑期班了
Rumour has it... you did summer school.
对 学化学 我爸说提前点儿好
Yep. Chemistry. My father thought I should get ahead.
你暑假过得怎么样
How was your summer, slick?
还不赖
Keen.
米克斯 把门关上
Meeks. Door. Closed.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
各位 我们四大支柱是什么
Gentlemen, what are the Four Pillars?
嘲弄 恐怖 颓废 排泄
Travesty. Horror. Decadence. Excrement.
好了 学习小组
Okay. Study group.
米克斯的拉丁不赖 英语我不怕
Meeks aced Latin. I didn't quite flunk English.
- 所以 如果你愿意 我们算一个组  - 没问题
- If you want, we got our study group.  - Sure.
卡梅伦也问我了 把他也算进来怎么样
Cameron asked me too. Anyone mind including him?
他什么东西拿手 拍马屁
Hmm, what's his specialty? Bootlicking?
- 好了 他是你室友  - 那可不是我的错
- Come on, he's your roommate.  - That's not my fault.
对不起 我叫史蒂芬・米克斯
I'm sorry. My name is Stephen Meeks.
他叫托德・安德森
Oh! This is Todd Anderson.
- 很高兴见到你  - 很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you.  - Nice to meet you.
查理・多尔顿
Charlie Dalton.
诺克斯・奥弗斯特里特
Knox Overstreet.
杰弗里・安德森是托德的哥哥
Todd's brother was Jeffrey Anderson.
- 是吗  - 你知道他什么
- Oh, yeah, sure.  - What do you know?
- 毕业生代表 全国优秀学生  - 嗯
- Valedictorian. National Merit Scholar.  - Oh, well...
欢迎到地狱来
welcome to Hell-ton.
这鬼地方可不好混 除非是米克斯一样的天才
It's every bit as tough as they say unless you're a genius like Meeks.
他会怕 不然也不帮他学拉丁语
He flatters me. That's why I help him with Latin.
还有英语 还有几何
And English. And trig.
门开着
It's open.
爸爸 我以为你走了
Father, I thought you'd gone.
- 佩里先生  - 坐着吧 孩子们
- Mr Perry.  - Keep your seats, fellows.
尼尔 我刚和诺兰先生谈过了
Neil, I've just spoken to Mr Nolan.
我觉得你这个学期课外活动太多了
You're taking too many extracurricular activities this semester
我看你不要参加校史年鉴的事了
and I've decided that you should drop the school annual.
但我今年是助理编辑
But I'm the assistant editor this year.
- 我看算了 尼尔  - 但是爸爸 这不行
- Well, I'm sorry, Neil.  - But, Father, I can't.
- 这不公平  - 孩子们 我们得单独谈一下
- It wouldn't be fair.  - Would you excuse us for a moment?
别公开跟我顶撞 明白吗
Don't you ever dispute me in public. Do you understand?
- 爸爸 我不是顶撞...  - 等你读完医科大学...
- Father, I wasn't disputing...  - After you've finished medical school...
自立了 你想干什么就干什么
and you're on your own, then you can do as you damn well please.
但在那之前 你得听我的 明白了吗
But until then, you do as I tell you. Is that clear?
明白 对不起
Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
你知道这对你妈妈有多重要 对不对
You know how much this means to your mother, don't you?
是
Yes, sir.
你知道的 我总喜欢找事
You know me always taking on too much.
好了 这就对了
Well, that's my boy.
- 需要什么尽管说  - 好的
- You need anything, you let us know.  - Yes, sir.
他干嘛不让你做想做的事
Why doesn't he let you do what you want?
对 尼尔 跟他吵 别什么大不了的
Yeah, Neil. Tell him off. Couldn't get any worse.
荒唐 就像你们跟父母吵
Oh, that's rich. Like you guys tell your parents off?
未来的律师先生 未来的银行家先生
Mr Future Lawyer and Mr Future Banker?
好了 其实我也不喜欢那么做
Okay, so I don't like it any more than you do.
好了 别教我怎么跟父亲说话就行了
Well, just don't tell me how to talk to my father.
- 你们都一个样  - 好了 好了 天哪
- You guys are the same way.  - All right, all right.Jesus.
- 那你准备怎么办  - 别无选择
- So what are you gonna do then?  - What I have to do.
- 放弃呗  - 要说这事 我也不会想太多
- Drop the annual.  - I wouldn't lose much sleep over it.
就是帮疯子想编点哗众取宠的东西呗
It's just a bunch of jerks trying to impress Nolan.
好了 我也根本不在乎
I don't care. I don't give a damn about any of it.
- 嗯 拉丁 八点在我宿舍  - 好
- Well, uh... Latin, 8:00 in my room?  - Yes.
- 听起来不错呀  - 托德 也欢迎你参加
- That sounds okay.  - Todd, you're welcome to join us.
- 对 一起来吧  - 谢谢
- Yeah, come along, pal.  - Thanks.
慢点儿 孩子们
Slow down, boys!
慢点儿 你们这帮毛手毛脚的家伙
Slow down, you horrible phalanx of pubescence!
从项目表上选三个实验项目...
Pick three laboratory experiments from the project list...
每五周写份报告
and report on them every five weeks.
第一章的前二十个问题明天交
The first 20 questions at the end of chapter one are due tomorrow.
- 埃格利科隆  - 埃格利科隆
- Agricolam.  - Agricolam.
- 埃格利科拉  - 埃格利科拉
- Agricola.  - Agricola.
- 埃格利科利  - 埃格利科利
- Agricolae.  - Agricolae.
- 埃格利科让  - 埃格利科让
- Agricolarum.  - Agricolarum.
- 埃格利科利斯  - 埃格利科利斯
- Agricolis.  - Agricolis.
- 埃格利科拉斯  - 埃格利科拉斯
- Agricolas.  - Agricolas.
- 埃格利科利斯  - 埃格利科利斯
- Agricolis.  - Agricolis.
- 再来一遍 埃格利科拉  - 埃格利科拉
- Again, please. Agricola.  - Agricola.
学习几何要求非常精确
Your study of trigonometry requires absolute precision.
任何人不按时完成作业...
Anyone failing to turn in any homework assignment...
都将会被扣掉一个学分
will be penalized one point off their final grade.
奉劝你们不要以身试法
Let me urge you now not to test me on this point.
笨蛋 笨蛋
Hey, Spaz. Spaz.
脑损伤
Brain damage!
嘘...
Shh!
嗯 来吧
Well, come on.
- 走吧  - 走吧 伙计们
- Let's go.  - Let's go, guys.
走吧
Let's go.
"哦 船长 我的船长"
"O Captain, my Captain."
有谁知道出自哪儿吗
Who knows where that comes from?
有吗
Anybody?
没人知道
Not a clue?
出自沃尔特・惠特曼为亚伯拉罕・林肯写的一首诗
It's from a poem by Walt Whitman about Mr Abraham Lincoln.
听好 在班上你们可以叫我基丁老师...
Now in this class you can either call me Mr Keating...
或者有胆量的话就叫"哦 船长 我的船长"
or, if you're slightly more daring, "O Captain, my Captain."
我首先要消除一些谣言 免得误人子弟
Now, let me dispel a few rumours so they don't fester into facts.
没错 我也上过这所地狱学校并活了下来
Yes, I, too, attended Hell-ton and survived.
不过 那时候我可不是你们现在看到的思想巨人
And, no, at that time, I was not the mental giant you see before you.
我的智慧跟一个九十八磅重的弱智差不多
I was the intellectual equivalent of a 98-pound weakling.
我到海滩念诗 人们会把拜伦诗集往我脸上砸
I would go to the beach, and people would kick copies of Byron in my face.
好了... 皮茨
Now... Mr Pitts?
这名字太不幸了
That's a rather unfortunate name.
皮茨 哪位是皮茨
Mr Pitts, where are you?
皮茨 把诗集翻到第五百四十二页
Mr Pitts, would you open your hymnal to page 542.
念一下那首诗的第一节
Read the first stanza of the poem you find there.
"劝少女们珍惜时光"
"To the Virgins to Make Much of Time"?
对 就是那首
Yes, that's the one.
对你们很合适 对吧
Somewhat appropriate, isn't it?
"及时采拮你的花蕾"
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may.
"旧时光一去不回"
"Old Time is still a-flying.
"今天尚在微笑的花朵 明日便在风中枯萎"
And this same flower that smiles today, tomorrow will be dying."
谢谢你 皮茨
Thank you, Mr Pitts.
"及时采拮你的花蕾"
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may."
这种感慨用拉丁语说 就叫"卡匹迪恩"
The Latin term for that sentiment is "Carpe diem."
有谁知道是什么意思吗
Now, who knows what that means?
"卡匹迪恩"也就是抓紧时间
Carpe diem. That's "Seize the day."
- 很好 你叫...  - 米克斯
- Very good, Mister...  - Meeks.
又一个不寻常的名字
Meeks. Another unusual name.
抓紧时间
Seize the day.
"及时采拮你的花蕾"
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may."
为什么作者要写这几句话
Why does the writer use these lines?
- 因为他很着急  - 不 叮
- Because he's in a hurry.  - No! Ding!
不过还是要感谢你的幽默
Thank you for playing anyway.
因为我们是蛆虫的食物
Because we are food for worms, lads.
因为不管你信不信 在这儿的每一个人...
Because, believe it or not, each and every one of us in this room...
有一天都会停止呼吸 变冷 死亡
is one day going to stop breathing, turn cold and die.
你们到前面来
I would like you to step forward over here...
好好看看过去的面孔
and peruse some of the faces from the past.
你们从这儿经过多次了
You've walked past them many times.
但肯定没有仔细看过
I don't think you've really looked at them.
他们和你们差别不大 对吧
They're not that different from you, are they?
同样的发型
Same haircuts.
充满活力 和你们一样
Full of hormones, just like you.
野心勃勃 和你们一样 世界在他们手中
Invincible, just like you feel. The world is their oyster.
相信自己一定能成就伟大的事业 就像你们很多人一样
They believe they're destined for great things, just like many of you.
他们眼中充满希望 就像你们一样
Their eyes are full of hope, just like you.
但他们是不是就曾经蹉跎而错过...
Did they wait until it was too late...
他们本可能成就的任何事业
to make from their lives even one iota of what they were capable?
因为 你瞧 各位 当年的年轻人已变成了花下之尘
Because, you see, gentlemen, these boys are now fertilizing daffodils.
但如果仔细听...
But if you listen real close...
你们还能听见他们给你们留下的忠告
you can hear them whisper their legacy to you.
来吧 近一点听
Go on, lean in.
听见了吗
Listen. Do you hear it?
卡匹
Carpe.
听见了吗
Hear it?
卡匹
Carpe.
卡匹迪恩
Carpe diem.
抓紧时间 孩子们
Seize the day, boys.
让你的生命不同寻常
Make your lives extraordinary.
- 太怪了  - 但与众不同
- That was weird.  - But different.
是吓人 要我说的话
Spooky, if you ask me.
你觉得这会考吗
Think he'll test us on that stuff?
行了 卡梅伦 你什么也没听明白
Oh, come on, Cameron. Don't you get anything?
什么 什么
What? What?
走吧 孩子们 动作快点儿 说你呢 多尔顿
Let's go, boys. Hustle up in here. That means you, Dalton!
好了 今晚几何学习小组谁参加
Who's up for a quick study group tonight, guys?
- 我  - 什么
- Me.  - What?
我去不了了 今晚我得去丹伯里家吃饭
I can't make it, guys. I have to have dinner at the Danburrys' house tonight.
丹伯里家 谁是丹伯里
The Danburrys? Who are the Danburrys?
废话 关你什么事
Big alums. How'd you swing that?
我爸的朋友 可能都九十多岁了
Friends of my dad's. They're probably in their nineties or something.
总比呆在地狱学校强 诺克斯
Anything's better than Hell-ton hash, Knox.
- 说的没错  - 嗯 我们明白
- I'll second that.  - Yeah, we'll see.
今晚活动你参加吗
You coming to the study group tonight?
不 我... 有点历史作业要做
Uh... no. No, I... Uh, I've got some history I wanna do.
随便你吧
Suit yourself.
好了吗 奥弗斯特里特
Ready, Overstreet?
可以走了
Ready to go, sir.
切特 你去开门吧
Chet, can you get that?
- 我忙着呢 妈  - 我去开
- I can't, Mom.  - I'll get it!
请问你找谁
Can I help you?
嗨 我是诺克斯・奥弗斯特里特
Hi. Knox Overstreet.
黑格博士
Uh, Dr Hager.
这是丹伯里家吧
This is the Danburrys', right?
- 你是来找切特的  - 丹伯里太太
- Are you here to see Chet?  - Mrs Danburry?
- 不  - 我是丹伯里太太
- No.  - Sorry. Thank you. I'm Mrs Danburry.
- 你是诺克斯吧  - 对
- You must be Knox.  - Yes.
九点前回去 进来吧 快进来
Back by 9:00? Please, come on in.
- 克里丝 你在干嘛  - 切特 我来了
- Chris, come on!  - Chet, I'm coming.
诺克斯 你好吗 乔・丹伯里
Knox. How are you? Joe Danburry.
- 很高兴见到您  - 他简直跟他父亲一个样
- Nice to meet you, sir.  - He's the spitting image of his father.
- 他怎么样 进来吧  - 克里丝
- How is he? Come on in.  - Chris!
- 他挺好 刚办了件大案  - 这也是你的志向吧
- Great. He just did a big case for G.M.  - I know where you're headed.
- 我来了  - 有其父 必有其子
- I'm coming.  - Like father, like son, huh?
神经病
Ooh! Psycho!
- 换个游戏玩  - 什么意思
- Another game?  - What do you mean?
用X和Y替换这些数字
just replace these numbers here with 'x, "for 'x"and 'y."
- 当然  - 当然 那还有什么问题
- Of course.  - Of course. So what's the problem?
- 等一下  - 吃得怎么样
- Wait. No.  - How was dinner?
- 吃得怎么样  - 糟透了
- How was dinner?  - Terrible.
- 难受  - 为什么 出什么事了
- Awful.  - Why? What happened?
今晚 我见到了我一辈子见过的最漂亮的女孩
Tonight, I met the most beautiful girl I have ever seen in my entire life.
你疯了吗 这有什么不好的
Are you crazy? What's wrong with that?
她差不多已经和切特・丹伯里订婚了
She's practically engaged to Chet Danburry.
那家伙该死
That guy could eat a football.
- 不好  - 不好
- Too bad.  - "Too bad"?
这比不好糟多了 这是个悲剧
It's worse than "too bad," Pittsie. It's a tragedy.
这么漂亮的女孩居然爱上了那么个傻瓜
A girl this beautiful in love with such a jerk.
所有漂亮妞都喜欢傻瓜 这你知道
All the good ones go for jerks. You know that.
对 忘了她 打开你的几何书 想一下第五题
Yeah, forget her. Open your trig book and try and figure out problem five.
我忘不了她 卡梅伦
I can't just forget her, Cameron.
现在也不可能做几何题
And I certainly can't think about trig.
成功了
We got it!
好了 各位 五分钟
All right, gentlemen. Five minutes.
走吧
Let's go.
- 你见她裸体了吗  - 别胡说 多尔顿
- Did you see her naked?  - Very funny, Dalton.
你腿上不是个收音机吧
That wouldn't be a radio in your lap
- 皮茨  - 不是 科学实验
- would it, Mr Pitts?  - No, sir. Science experiment.
雷达
Radar.
各位 翻到前言第二十一页
Gentlemen, open your text to page 21 of the introduction.
佩里 你念一下序言
Mr Perry, will you read the opening paragraph of the preface
"诗歌鉴赏"的第一段
entitled "Understanding Poetry."
"诗歌鉴赏" 作者 J・埃文斯・普里查特博士
"'Understand Poetry" by Dr J. Evans Pritchard, Ph.D.
"要完全理解诗歌 我们首先必须了解..."
"To fully understand poetry, we must first be fluent...
"它的格调 韵律和修辞手法"
"with its metre, rhyme and figures of speech.
"然后提两个问题"
"Then ask two questions.
"第一 诗歌的主题是如何艺术地实现的"
"One: How artfully has the objective of the poem been rendered?
"第二 该主题的重要性如何"
'And, two: How important is that objective?
"第一个问题解决的是诗歌的艺术性"
"Question one rates the poem's perfection.
"第二个问题回答的是它的重要性"
"Question two rates its importance.
"一旦弄清这两个问题"
'And once these questions have been answered...
"判断该诗的优劣也就不是个太难的问题了"
"determining a poem's greatness becomes a relatively simple matter.
"如果把诗歌艺术性的得分画在图表的横轴上"
"If the poem's score for perfection is plotted on the horizontal of a graph...
"把它的重要性记在竖轴上"
"and its importance is plotted on the vertical"
"计算一下所覆盖的面积"
"then calculating the total area of the poem...
"也就得出了它的优劣"
"yields the measure of its greatness.
"拜伦的十四行诗可能在竖轴上得分很高"
"A sonnet by Byron might score high on the vertical,
"但横向得分一般"
"but only average on the horizontal.
"而莎士比亚的十四行诗"
'A Shakespearean sonnet, on the other hand
"可能在横向和竖向上都得分很高"
"would score high both horizontally and vertically,
"覆盖的面积很大"
yielding a massive total area
"也就表明它是一首优秀的诗歌"
thereby revealing the poem to be truly great.
"阅读本书的诗歌时 请练习这种分析方法"
'As you proceed through the poetry in this book, practise this rating method.
"随着你用这种方法评价诗歌的能力不断提高"
'As your ability to evaluate poems in this manner grows
"对诗歌的欣赏和理解也会日益提高"
so will... so will your enjoyment and understanding of poetry."
屁话
Excrement.
这就是我对 J・埃文斯・普里查特先生的评价
That's what I think of Mr J. Evans Pritchard.
我们不是在安水管 我们是在谈论诗歌
We're not laying pipe. We're talking about poetry.
我意思是 你怎么评论像美国诗人班德斯坦的诗呢
I mean, how can you describe poetry like American Bandstand?
"我喜欢拜伦 我给他四十二分 但并不为之欣喜"
"I like Byron. I give him a 42. But I can't dance to it."
现在 我要你们把那一页撕了
Now, I want you to rip out that page.
撕吧 把整页都撕了
Go on. Rip out the entire page.
没听见吗 把它撕了
You heard me. Rip it out.
把它撕了
Rip it out!
快点 撕了它
Go on. Rip it out.
谢谢你 多尔顿
Thank you, Mr Dalton.
各位 听我说 不只是要撕掉那一页
Gentlemen, tell you what. Don't just tear out that page.
把整个前言都撕了 我不想再见到它
Tear out the entire introduction. I want it gone, history. Leave nothing.
全都撕了 撕了它 再见了
Rip it out! Rip! Be gone,
J・埃文斯・普里查特博士
J. Evans Pritchard, Ph.D.!
撕 扯 拽
Rip! Shred! Tear!
撕了它 我只想听到撕书的声音
Rip it out! I want to hear nothing but ripping of Mr Pritchard!
在上面打个孔串成一串
We'll perforate it, put it on a roll!
这不是《圣经》 你们不会因此下地狱
It's not the Bible. You're not gonna go to hell for this.
继续 撕干净点儿 什么也不要剩
Go on. Make a clean tear. I want nothing left of it.
不能损坏书籍
We shouldn't be doing this.
撕 撕 撕
Rip! Rip! Rip!
撕了它 撕
Rip it out! Rip!
撕了它 对 撕了它
Rip it! Yeah! Rip it out!
- 撕了它  - 这是怎么回事
- Rip it!  - What the hell is going on here?
- 撕得还不够响  - 基丁先生
- I don't hear enough rips.  - Mr Keating.
麦卡利斯特先生
Mr McAllister.
对不起 我... 我不知道你在这儿
I'm sorry, I... I didn't know you were here.
- 我在  - 对不起
- I am.  - Ah. So you are.
打扰了
Excuse me.
继续撕 各位
Keep ripping, gentlemen.
这是一场战斗 战争
This is a battle, a war.
受害的可能是你们的思想和灵魂
And the casualties could be your hearts and souls.
谢谢你 多尔顿
Thank you, Mr Dalton.
学院派在不断向诗歌发起进攻
Armies of academics going forward measuring poetry.
不 我们不能答应
No! We will not have that here.
让 J・埃文斯・普里查特见鬼去吧
No more of Mr J. Evans Pritchard.
现在 各位你们要学会自己思考
Now, my class, you will learn to think for yourselves again.
你们要学会欣赏文字和语言
You will learn to savour words and language.
不管别人怎么说
No matter what anybody tells you
文字和语言的确能改变世界
words and ideas can change the world.
我发觉皮茨的眼神好像在说...
I see that look in Mr Pitts' eye...
十九世纪文学跟上商学院
like 19th century literature has nothing to do with
或者医学院没有关系
going to business school or medical school.
对吧 也许
Right? Maybe.
霍普金斯你可能也这么想 认为...
Mr Hopkins, you may agree with him, thinking,
"对 我们应该老老实实学学...
"Yes, we should simply study our Mr Pritchard...
普里查特的理论格调韵律什么的
"and learn our rhyme and metre and go quietly about the business...
然后再去实现我们的其他理想"
of achieving other ambitions."
我有个秘密要告诉你 靠扰来
I have a little secret for you. Huddle up.
靠扰来
Huddle up!
我们读诗写诗 并不是因为它好玩
We don't read and write poetry because it's cute.
我们读诗写诗是因为我们是人类的一分子
We read and write poetry because we are members of the human race.
而人类是充满激情的
And the human race is filled with passion.
没错 医学 法律 商业 工程
Medicine, law, business, engineering:
这些都是崇高的追求 足以支撑人的一生
these are noble pursuits and necessary to sustain life.
但诗歌...
But poetry,
美丽 浪漫 爱情...
beauty, romance, love...
这些才是我们生活的意义
these are what we stay alive for.
惠特曼曾写道
To quote from Whitman.
"自我 生命 这些问题总在不停出现"
"O me, O life of the questions of these recurring.
"毫无信仰的人群川流不息"
"Of the endless trains of the faithless.
"城市充斥着愚昧"
"Of cities filled with the foolish.
"生活在其中有什么意义 自我 生命"
"What good amid these, O me, O life?
答案是 因为你的存在
"Answer: That you are here.
因为你的存在
"That life exists and identity.
因为伟大的戏剧在继续
"That the powerful play goes on,
因为你可以奉献一首诗
and you may contribute a verse."
因为伟大的戏剧在继续
"That the powerful play goes on,
因为你可以奉献一首诗
and you may contribute a verse."
你的诗是什么
What will your verse be?
为我们即将获得的一切
For what we are about to receive
愿主让我们心存感激
may the Lord make us truly grateful.
阿门
Amen.
你今天课上得很有意思 基丁先生
Quite an interesting class you gave today, Mr Keating.
- 抱歉吓了你一跳 麦卡利斯特先生  - 用不着道歉
- Sorry if I shocked you, Mr McAllister.  - There's no need to apologise.
很有意思 虽然有些误导
It was very fascinating, misguided though it was.
是吗
You think so?
你鼓励他们成为艺术家是很冒险的 约翰
You take a big risk by encouraging them to become artists, John.
等他们意识到他们不是伦勃朗 莎士比亚或者莫扎特
When they realize that they're not Rembrandts, Shakespeares or Mozarts
他们会因此恨你的
they'll hate you for it.
不是让他们当艺术家 乔治 自由思想者
We're not talking artists, George. We're talking freethinkers.
十七岁的自由思想者
Freethinkers at 17?
奇怪 没想到你这么悲观
Funny, I never pegged you as a cynic.
不是悲观
Not a cynic.
是现实
A realist.
他们真能不满脑子胡思乱想
"Show me the heart unfettered by foolish dreams
我也就不会悲观了
and I'll show you a happy man."
只有在梦想中 人才能真正自由
"But only in their dreams can men be truly free.
从来如此也将永远如此
'Twas always thus, and always thus will be."
坦尼森
Tennyson?
不 基丁
No. Keating.
嘿 我在图书馆找到了他的记录
Hey, I found his senior annual in the library.
听好 足球队队长
Listen to this. Captain of the soccer team.
校史年鉴编辑 考入剑桥大学
Editor of the school annual. Cambridge bound.
性格温和 死亡诗人俱乐部成员
Thigh man and the Dead Poets Society.
充满幻想 敢做敢为
"Man Most Likely To Do Anything."
性格温和 他能把人吓死
Thigh man? Mr "K" was a hell-raiser.
什么叫死亡诗人俱乐部
What's the Dead Poets Society?
- 不知道  - 年鉴上有照片吗
- I don't know.  - Is there a picture in the annual?
- 没有 这事别再提了  - 那边那个
- Nothing. No other mention of it.  - That boy there,
午饭后来见我
see me after lunch.
基丁老师
Mr Keating?
先生
Sir?
- 说点什么  - 哦 船长 我的船长
- Say something.  - O Captain, my Captain?
你们好
Gentlemen.
我们刚看到了你的记录
We were just looking in your old annual.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
不 那不是我
No, that's not me.
斯坦利・威尔逊
Stanley "The Tool" Wilson.
- 天哪  - 什么是死亡诗人俱乐部
- God.  - What was the Dead Poets Society?
现在的学校不会认为那是个什么好组织
I doubt the present administration would look too favourably upon that.
为什么 那到底是什么
Why? What was it?
- 各位 你们能保密吗  - 当然
- Gentlemen, can you keep a secret?  - Sure.
"死亡诗人致力于吸取生命的精华"
The Dead Poets were dedicated to sucking the marrow out of life.
这是我们每次开会前都要引用的梭罗的一句话
That's a phrase from Thoreau we'd invoke at the beginning of every meeting.
我们经常在印地安山洞聚会
You see, we would gather at the old Indian cave...
轮流朗诵梭罗 惠特曼 雪莱等诗人的作品
and take turns reading from Thoreau, Whitman, Shelley... the biggies.
甚至我们自己的诗作
Even some of our own verse.
在那种痴迷的时刻 诗歌有着一种神奇的作用
And in the enchantment of the moment, we'd let poetry work its magic.
你是说那也就是一帮坐在一起念诗的人
You mean it was a bunch of guys sitting around, reading poetry?
不 奥弗斯特里特 并不像你想象的那样
No, Mr Overstreet. It wasn't just guys.
那并不是个很严密的组织 是一群浪漫主义者
We weren't a Greek organization. We were romantics.
我们不仅仅是念诗 诗从我们舌间滑落 就像蜜糖
We didn't just read poetry, we let it drip from our tongues, like honey.
情绪高涨 女人亢奋 灵魂驰骋
Spirits soared, women swooned and gods were created, gentlemen.
这么度过一个夜晚也还不错
Not a bad way to spend an evening, eh?
嗯
Hmm.
谢谢你 佩里 让我回想这么多过去的事
Thank you, Mr Perry, for this stroll down amnesia lane.
烧了它
Burn that.
尤其是我那张照片
Especially my picture.
死亡诗人俱乐部
Dead Poets Society.
什么
What?
- 我们今天晚上去  - 今晚
- I say we go tonight.  - Tonight?
- 等一下  - 有谁参加
- Wait a minute.  - Everybody in?
- 他说的山洞在哪儿  - 就在河那边
- Where's this cave he's talking about?  - It's beyond the stream.
- 我知道在哪儿  - 那远着呢
- I know where it is.  - That's miles.
- 我看没什么意思  - 别去了
- Sounds boring to me.  - Don't go.
知道这会被扣掉多少学分吗 多尔顿
You know how many demerits we're talking?
那你就别去 行吗
So don't come. Please.
好了 我只是说我们得小心
Look, all I'm saying is that we have to be careful.
- 不能让人抓住  - 当然 真嗦
- We can't get caught.  - No shit, Sherlock.
你们干嘛呢 快点
You boys there! Hurry up!
- 好了 谁参加  - 行了 尼尔 老师在看着呢
- All right, who's in?  - Aw, come on, Neil. Hager's...
别管他了 谁参加
Forget Hager! No! Who's in?
我参加
I'm in.
我警告你们 快点
I'm warning you! Move!
我也参加
Me too.
- 我不知道 尼尔  - 什么 皮茨
- I don't know, Neil.  - What? Pitts!
- 皮茨 好啦  - 他功课太紧
- Pittsie, come on.  - His grades are hurting.
你可以帮他 米克斯
You can help him, Meeks.
这算什么 午夜学习小组
What is this, a midnight study group?
行啦 皮茨 参加吧 米克斯 你功课也紧吗
Forget it, Pitts. You're coming. Meeks, your grades hurting too?
- 什么我都不怕  - 除了女孩
- I'll try anything once.  - Except sex.
只要小心点我就参加
I'm in as long as we're careful.
- 你怎么样 诺克斯  - 我不知道 查理
- What about you, Knox?  - I don't know, Charlie.
好啦 诺克斯 这对你追克里丝有好处
Come on, Knox. It'll help you get Chris.
是吗 为什么
Yeah? How?
- 女人亢奋  - 但她们为什么亢奋
- Women swoon.  - But why do they swoon?
查理 告诉我她们为什么亢奋
Charlie, tell me why they swoon! Charlie!
沿着小河走到瀑布
Okay, follow the stream to the waterfall.
就在这儿 肯定就在那儿的河岸上
It's right there. It's got to be on the banks.
我不知道 我开始觉得这挺危险了
I don't know. This is starting to sound dangerous.
- 那你干嘛不呆在家里  - 什么 你疯了
- Oh, well, why don't you stay home?  - Hey, you're crazy.
看在上帝份上 别再嘀咕了 坐好
For God's sake, stop chattering and sit down.
- 托德 你今晚去吗  - 不
- Todd, are you coming tonight?  - No.
为什么 托德 你当时也在 你听见他说的了
Why not? God, you were there. You heard Keating.
- 你就不想做点什么吗  - 想
- Don't you want to do something about that?  - Yes.
- 但是...  - 但是 但是什么
- But...  - But? But what?
基丁说每个人要轮流念诗
Keating said that everybody took turns reading
但我不想念诗
and I don't want to do that.
念诗对你还真有什么问题吗
Gosh, you really have a problem with that, don't you?
不 没什么问题
N... No, I don't have a problem.
尼尔 我只是... 只是不想念 行吗
Neil, I just... I don't want to do it, okay?
好吧
All right.
如果你不用念呢 如果只要你去听呢
What if you didn't have to read? What if you just came and listened?
- 但那不是正常做法  - 好啦 管它什么做法呢
- That's not how it works.  - Well, forget how it works.
如果... 如果他们说可以呢
What if... What if they said it was okay?
什么 你要去问他们是不是
What... What, are you gonna go up and ask them?
不 尼尔
No. No, Neil.
- 我就回来  - 尼尔 尼尔
- I'll be right back.  - Neil. Neil!
闭嘴 行吗
Oh, shut up, will you?
那是我治哮喘的 行吗
That's for my asthma, okay?
把那还给我 行吗
Could you give that back, please?
什么事 你不喜欢蛇吗
What's the matter? Don't you like snakes?
- 你参加  - 别来烦我 行吗
- You're in.  - Get away from me, okay?
你干嘛不翻翻你口袋
Why don't you check your pocket, huh?
- 我要刷牙了  - 走开
- Come on. I have to brush my teeth.  - Get a... Get off.
你们别瞎嚷嚷了
Cut out that racket in there!
《诗歌五百年》
J・基丁 死亡诗人俱乐部
死亡诗人俱乐部聚会朗诵辞
走 走
Go. Go.
- 我是死亡诗人  - 见鬼 查理
- I'm a dead poet!  - Aw, shit, Charlie.
- 各位 就是这儿  - 别闹 别瞎嚷
- Guys! Over here!  - Funny. You're real funny.
太潮湿了
It's too wet.
你想把我们都熏跑啊
God, are you trying to smoke us out of here?
不 不 烟会从这儿出去的
No, no. The smoke's going right up this opening.
你没事吧
You okay?
哦 天哪 熏死了
Oh, God. Clowns.
好了 别生火了
All right, forget the fire.
开始了 各位
Let's go, gentlemen.
死亡诗人俱乐部今天正式恢复
I hereby reconvene the Dead Poets Society
威尔顿分部
Welton Chapter.
聚会将又由我
The meetings will be conducted by myself
以及在座的各位新会员主持
and the other new initiates now present.
托德・安德森 因为他不愿念诗
Todd Anderson, because he prefers not to read
将担任会议记录
will keep minutes of the meetings.
现在我将朗诵俱乐部会员
I'll now read the traditional opening message...
亨利・戴维・梭罗所作的开幕辞
by Society member Henry David Thoreau.
"我步入丛林 因为我希望生活有意义"
"I went to the woods because I wanted to live deliberately.
"我希望活得深刻 吸取生命中所有精华"
I wanted to live deep and suck out all the marrow of life."
我同意
I'll second that.
"把非生命的一切都击溃"
"To put to rout all that was not life.
"以免 当我生命终结"
"And not, when I had come to die,
"发现自己从没有活过"
discover that I had not lived."
- 基丁标了其他好几页  - 好了 会议休息
- Keating's marked a bunch of other pages.  - All right, intermission!
往下挖 就是这儿 铺在这儿
Dig deep. Right here. Right here, lay it down.
放地上 你在说什么 放地上
On the mud? We're gonna put our food on the mud?
米克斯 把你衣服脱了 当野餐桌布
Meeks, put your coat down. Picnic blanket.
用米克斯的衣服
Use Meeks' coat.
别藏藏掖掖的了
Don't keep anything back either.
- 我的烟不全分给你们抽了吗  - 葡萄干
- You guys are always bumming my smokes.  - Raisins?
- 是啊  - 等一下
- Yuck.  - Wait a minute!
- 谁给的半个面包  - 另一半我在吃呢
- Who gave us half a roll?  - I'm eating the other half.
- 拿来  - 什么 你要我放回去
- Come on!  - What, you want me to put it back?
这是一个漆黑的雨夜
It was a dark and rainy night, and this old lady
这位酷爱拼板游戏的老妇人
who had a passion for jigsaw puzzles
独自一人坐在家里 在桌上摆最新的拼板
sat by herself in her house at her table to complete a new jigsaw puzzle.
当她把拼板拼起来
But as she pieced the puzzle together
她惊奇地发现
she realized, to her astonishment,
构成的图案就是她自己的房间
that the image that was formed was her very own room.
拼图中间的人像
And the figure in the centre of the puzzle
居然就是她自己
as she completed it, was herself.
双手颤抖着 她把最后四块放上去...
And with trembling hands, she placed the last four pieces...
恐惧地发现窗户上有一张疯子的脸
and stared in horror at the face of a demented madman at the window.
这位老妇人最后听到的...
The last thing that this old lady ever heard...
- 是玻璃碎裂的声音  - 这不是真的
- was the sound of breaking glass.  - No, she didn't.
这是真的 这是真的
Yes, this is true. This is true.
我有个故事比这还精彩
I've got one that's better than that.
真的 有一对年轻的夫妇
I do. There's a young, married couple
他们晚上开车穿过一片森林
and they're driving through the forest at night on a long trip.
他们汽车没油了 有一个疯子...
And they run out of gas, and there's a madman on the...
手里拿着件东西
The thing with the hand?
这故事才精彩
I love that story!
- 是我告诉你的  - 不是的
- I told you that one.  - You did not.
- 是我六年级在夏令营听说的  - 去年
- I got that in camp in sixth grade.  - Last year?
很久以前 在山林路边
"In a mean abode in the Shanking Road
住着一个淳朴的农夫
"lived a man named William Bloat.
他有个妻子 是他一生的痛苦
"Now, he had a wife, the plague of his life
总让他觉得生不如死
"who continually got his goat.
有一天黎明 趁妻子睡意末醒
"And one day at dawn, with her nightshift on
他掐断了她的生命
he slit her bloody throat."
什么玩意
Oh, and it gets worse.
想听首真正的诗吗
You want to hear a real poem?
- 给你吧  - 不 我不用 你拿着吧
- You want this?  - No, I don't need... Get this outta here.
- 什么 你也带了一本  - 你还能背诗
- What, did you bring one?  - You memorized a poem?
我没有背诗
You memorized a poem?
- 查理・多尔顿原创作品  - 原创作品
- An original piece by Charlie Dalton.  - An original piece.
- 站在中间去  - 真的 这真是开天辟地
- Take centre stage.  - You know, this is history, right?
哇哦
Wow. Whoa.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where did you get that?
你从哪儿...
Where did you...
- 哇  - 教我恋爱
- Whoa.  - "Teach me to love?
先教教你自己
"Go teach thyself more wit.
恋爱艺术属我第一
"I chief professor am of it.
恋爱之神 如果有这么种东西
"The god of love, if such a thing there be
也得先向我学习
may learn to love from me."
你写了那个
Wow. Did you write that?
亚伯拉罕・考利
Abraham Cowley.
好了 谁下一个
Okay. Who's next?
阿尔弗雷德・丁尼生
Alfred Lord Tennyson.
来吧 我的朋友
"Come, my friends.
寻找更新的世界尚为时不晚
"'Tis not too late to seek a newer world.
我决心已定 要驶过夕阳尽头
"For my purpose holds to sail beyond the sunset.
尽管我们不再有昔日的伟力
"And though we are not now that strength...
可以振天撼地
"which in old days moved Earth and heaven.
我们仍有着
"That which we are, we are:
同样的英雄的心
"one equal temper of heroic hearts...
时间和命运使它衰弱 但坚强意志仍在
"made weak by time and fate, but strong in will...
让我们去奋斗 去探索 去发现
"to strive, to seek, to find
永不屈服
and not to yield."
然后我有了信仰 然后我有了一种想象
"Then I had religion, then I had a vision.
我被他们对嘲笑的沉迷感染
"I could not turn from their revel in derision.
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
"Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林中划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track."
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
米克斯 米克斯
Meeks. Meeks.
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track.
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track.
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track!
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track!
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track!
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track!
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black,
在森林划下一道金色的沟壑
cutting through the forest with a golden track!
Cutting through the forest with a golden track!
然后我看见刚果河从黑土地蜿蜒流过
Then I saw the Congo creeping through the black...
不说一个人"很累" 而说他很"疲惫"
A man is not "very tired." He is "exhausted."
不用"不开心" 而用...
And don't use "very sad." Use...
来吧 奥弗斯特里特 你的高见
Come on, Mr Overstreet, you twerp.
- 阴郁  - 对极了 阴郁
- "Morose"?  - Exactly! Morose!
语言的发展只有一个目的 就是... 安德森
Language was developed for one endeavour, and that is... Mr Anderson?
来吧 是个男子汉 还是条变形虫
Come on, are you a man or an amoeba?
佩里 你来答
Mr Perry?
用来交流
Uh... to communicate.
不 用来追女人
No! To woo women.
今天我们要谈一谈...
Today we're going to be talking...
- 威廉・莎士比亚  - 哦 天呐
- about William Shakespeare.  - Oh, God.
我知道你们很多人都像
I know. A lot of you look forward to this...
讨厌牙科手术一样讨厌这个
about as much as you look forward to root canal work.
但我只会把莎士比亚...
We're gonna talk about Shakespeare...
当做一个写了些有意思的东西的人来谈
as someone who writes something very interesting.
你们很多人都看过莎士比亚这样的东西
Now, many of you have seen Shakespeare done very much like this:
"哦 泰特斯 把你的朋友带上来"
"O, Titus, bring your friend hither."
但如果你们有人看过马龙・白兰度
But if any of you have seen Mr Marlon Brando,
"莎士比亚可以有不同的演法"
you know that Shakespeare can be different.
"朋友们 公民们 同胞们 请听我说"
"Friends, Romans, countrymen, lend me your ears."
你们也可以想象约翰・韦恩扮演麦克帕斯
You can also imagine maybe John Wayne as Macbeth going...
"我面前的是一把剑吗"
"Well, is this a dagger I see before me?"
要狗吗 先生 哦 现在不要
"Dogs, sir? Oh, not just now.
我有时候的确喜欢来只狗
"I do enjoy a good dog once in a while, sir.
一只狗可以做成三道好菜
"You can have yourself a three-course meal from one dog.
首先是犬牙炸丸子
"Start with a canine croquette.
然后是火烧狗腿作为主菜
"Go to your Fido Flambe for main course.
甜点嘛 来道狮子狗水果冻
'And for dessert, a Pekingese parfait.
然后还可以用它的小爪子剔牙
And you can pick your teeth with the little paw."
我为什么要站到这儿
Why do I stand up here?
- 谁知道  - 感觉高一点
- Anybody?  - To feel taller.
不 谢谢你的幽默
No! Thank you for playing.
我站到讲台上...
I stand upon my desk...
是想提醒我自己我们必须时刻用不同的眼光来看待事物
to remind myself that we must constantly look at things in a different way.
瞧 从这上面看世界 完全不同
See, the world looks very different from up here.
如果不相信
You don't believe me?
可以自己来看 来吧
Come see for yourselves. Come on.
来吧 一旦你觉得自己懂得了什么
Come on.Just when you think you know something,
就必须换一种角度来看
you have to look at it in another way.
这可能显得很荒唐或者愚蠢
Even though it may seem silly or wrong,
但必须试一下
you must try.
同样 读书的时候不要只想作者怎么看
Now when you read, don't just consider what the author thinks.
想想你怎么看
Consider what you think.
同学们 你们必须努力寻找自己的声音
Boys, you must strive to find your own voice.
因为你越迟开始寻找
Because the longer you wait to begin,
找到的可能性就越小
the less likely you are to find it at all.
梭罗说"大多数人都生活在平静的绝望中"
Thoreau said, "Most men lead lives of quiet desperation."
别陷入这种境地 冲出来
Don't be resigned to that. Break out.
别像老鼠逃跑似的 看看你的周围
Don't just walk off the edge like lemmings. Look around you.
对了 就这样 布里斯克 谢谢
There you go, Mr Priske. Thank you!
对极了
Yes!
要敢于开拓新的天地
Dare to strike out and find new ground.
好了 除了写作文以外
Now, in addition to your essays,
我希望你们每人写一首诗 自己的诗
I would like you to compose a poem of your own, an original work.
这就对了
That's right.
每个人星期一早晨都要在全班念自己的诗
You have to deliver it aloud, in front of the class on Monday.
祝你们好运 各位
Bon chance, gentlemen.
安德森
Mr Anderson.
别以为我不知道这作业把你魂都吓没了
Don't think I don't know this assignment scares the hell out of you,
胆小鬼
you mole.
每两下用一次力
Take a power train in two!
三号 集中注意力
Three, keep your eyes in the boat!
成功了 皮茨
We got it, Pittsie.
自由美国电台
Radio Free America!
Some people like to rock Some people like to roll
But movin'and a-groovin' is gonna satisfy my soul
Let's have a party Oooh
Let's have a party
Let's spin it to the soul Let's rock and roll
Let's have a party tonight
I never kissed a bear I never kissed a goose
But I can shake a chicken in the middle of the room
Let's have a party
- 我找到了  - 找到什么了
- I found it.  - You found what?
我想干什么 就现在 我真正真正的梦想
What I want to do right now. What's really, really inside of me.
- "仲夏夜之梦"  - 对
- "A Midsummer Night's Dream."  - This is it.
- 这是什么  - 是一出戏 笨蛋
- What is that?  - It's a play, dummy.
这我知道 但是... 这跟你有什么关系
I know that. Wh... What does it have to do with you?
好吧 他们要在亨利会堂上演这出戏
All right, they're putting it on at Henley Hall.
欢迎试演 欢迎试演
Open tryouts. Open tryouts!
- 所以  - 所以
- Yeah, so?  - So!
我要演戏了
I'm gonna act.
演戏 演戏 我要当演员了
Yes! Yes! I'm gonna be an actor!
很早以前我就想试一试
Ever since I can remember, I've wanted to try this!
去年我还曾想参加暑期剧团试演
I even tried to go to summer stock auditions last year,
当然 我爸没让
but, of course, my father wouldn't let me.
我平生第一次知道了我到底想做什么
For the first time in my whole life, I know what I want to do.
也是第一次 我决心要做成...
And for the first time, I'm gonna do it...
不管我爸同不同意
whether my father wants me to or not!
- 卡匹迪恩  - 尼尔 尼尔 等一下
- Carpe diem!  - Neil, Neil, hold it.
如果你爸不让 你怎么去演戏呢
How are you gonna be in a play if your father won't let you?
我首先要争取到角色 然后再想这个问题
First, I gotta get the part, then I can worry about that.
但如果他发现你都没跟他说一声就去参加试演
But won't he kill you if he finds out you went to an audition
他还不杀了你
and didn't tell him?
不 不 不 照我看来
No, no, no. As far as I'm concerned,
根本用不着让他知道这件事
he won't have to know about any of this.
- 这不可能  - 不 没什么不可能
- Well, that's impossible.  - Bullshit. Nothing's impossible.
听我说 你干嘛不打个电话问问他 也许他会同意
Well, why don't you just call him and ask him and m-maybe he'll say yes.
简直笑话
That's a laugh.
如果不问他 至少我没违抗他的意愿
If I don't ask him, at least I won't be disobeying him.
是 但如果他以前就不同意...
Yeah, but if he said no before...
天哪 托德 你站在谁一边
Jesus, Todd, whose side are you on?
我意思是现在连角色还没弄到
I mean, I haven't even gotten the part yet.
我就不能先在脑子里过过瘾
Can't I even enjoy the idea for a little while?
- 你参加下午的聚会吗  - 我不知道 也许会
- You're coming to the meeting?  - I don't know. Maybe.
基丁老师的话对你狗屁不算 是吗 托德
Nothing Mr Keating has to say means shit to you, does it, Todd?
- 这... 这是什么意思  - 你是俱乐部成员
- Wh... What is that supposed to mean?  - You're in the club!
是成员就意味着充满激情
Being in the club means being stirred up by things.
但你看上去像一潭死水
You look about as stirred up as a cesspool.
- 你要我退出  - 我要你参与
- So you want me out?  - No, I want you in!
但参与意味着你得做点事情 不是光嘴上说
But being in means you gotta do something, not just say you're in.
听我说 尼尔 我是说谢谢你的关心
Listen, Neil, I mean, I appreciate this concern,
但是我和你不一样 对不对
but I'm not like you, all right?
你... 你... 你说话有人听
You... You... You say things and people listen.
我... 我... 我不一样
I... I... I'm not like that.
- 你觉得你做不到  - 是
- Don't you think you could be?  - No.
我... 我不知道 但问题还不在这儿
I... I... I don't know, but that's not the point.
问题是 这是没有办法的事 所以你就别管我了
The point is, there's nothing you can do about it, so you can just butt out.
我能照顾自己
I can take care of myself just fine.
行吗
All right?
不
No.
你是什么意思 不
What do you mean, "no"?
不
No.
还给我 尼尔
Give me that! Neil!
- 尼尔 还给我  - 我们梦想...
- Neil, give that back!  - "We are dreaming of a tomorrow..."
- 是一首诗  - 尼尔
- It's poetry!  - Neil!
追我的是个沃尔特・惠特曼
I'm being chased by Walt Whitman!
好了 好了
Okay! Okay!
你们在干嘛 我在做 这道化学...
What are you guys doing? I'm trying... You see this chemistry...
把书还给我 尼尔
Hey. Give me... Neil, give me...
给我别瞎胡闹了 快点
Don't be immature. Come on!
- 快给我...  - 还给我
- I need my...  - Give it to me!
查理
Charlie!
还给我 我要我的...
Let me have my book. I need my...
好了 全都上车
Okay, everybody on the bus.
走了 孩子们
Let's go, boys.
走啦 快上车 孩子们
Come on. Let's go. On the bus, boys.
上车
Now!
爱好运动的人...
Now, devotees may argue...
可能会觉得某一种运动就是比另一种强
that one sport or game is inherently better than another.
对我来说 运动只是一种让其他人...
For me, sport is actually a chance...
把我们推向极至的机会
for us to have other human beings push us to excel.
每个人都到这儿拿张纸条
I want you all to come over here and take a slip of paper...
然后排成一排
and line up single file.
米克斯 吸取大地的精华
Mr Meeks, time to inherit the Earth.
皮茨 让你的名字更响亮
Mr Pitts... rise above your name.
你把这些发下去 每人一张
I want you to hand these out to the boys, one a piece.
你知道怎么做
You know what to do, Pitts!
"与逆境不屈抗争 以无畏的气势面对敌人"
"Oh, to struggle against great odds, to meet enemies undaunted."
听上去像你已经吓坏了 拿出点气势来再念一通
Sounds like you're daunted. Say it again like you're undaunted.
"与逆境不屈地抗争 以无畏的气势面对敌人"
"Oh, to struggle against great odds, to meet enemies undaunted"!
好了 开始
Now go on!
好的 下一个
Yes! Next!
"做一个世界的水手 游遍所有的港口"
"To be a sailor of the world bound for all ports."
下一个 大声点儿
Next. Louder!
"哦 我要做生活的主宰 不是奴隶"
"Oh, I live to be the ruler of life, not a slave."
"走上绞刑台"
"To mount the scaffolds.
"迎向行刑的枪口 我自安之如泰"
To advance to the muzzles of guns with perfect nonchalance."
来吧 米克斯 听着音乐
Come on, Meeks! Listen to the music!
舞蹈 鼓掌 兴奋 欢叫 跳跃
"To dance, clap hands, exalt, shout, skip,
- 飘飘荡荡 滚滚向前  - 下一个
- roll on, float on!"  - Yes!
让生活从此变成一首欢乐的诗
"Oh, to have life henceforth, the poem of new joys."
快点 查理 让它充满你的灵魂
Come on, Charlie, let it fill your soul.
做一个真正的上帝
"To indeed be a god!"
查理 我争取到了
Charlie, I got the part!
我要扮演帕克
I'm gonna play Puck!
- 我要扮演帕克  - 他说什么
- I'm gonna play Puck!  - What did he say?
- 帕克  - 是主角
- Puck you!  - The main part!
- 太好了 尼尔  - 查理 我成功了
- Great, Neil!  - Charlie, I got it!
- 祝贺你 尼尔  - 很适合你 很适合你
- Congratulations.  - Good for you! Good for you!
好了 好了
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
尼尔 你到时怎么办
Neil, how are you gonna do this?
我需要一封我爸和诺兰先生的批准信
They need a letter of permission from my father and Mr Nolan.
- 你不会自己写吧  - 哦 不 我会
- You're not gonna write it.  - Oh, yes, I am.
尼尔 你疯了
Oh, Neil... Neil, you're crazy.
好了
Okay.
冒昧给您...
I am writing to you...
写这封信...
on behalf of...
是为我儿子...
my son...
尼尔・佩里的事
Neil Perry.
太棒了
This is great!
致克里丝
"To Chris."
谁是克里丝
Who's Chris? Mmm, Chris.
我在她微笑中看到甜蜜
"I see a sweetness in her smile.
她的眼睛闪烁着光芒
"Bright light shines from her eyes.
但生活是如此复杂 我已满意...
"But life is complete, contentment is mine...
只要知道...
"just knowing that...
"Just knowing that...
她还活着
she's alive."
对不起 我的船长 这太傻了
I'm sorry, Captain. It's stupid.
不 不 这并不傻
No. No, it's not stupid.
写得很好 它触及了一个重大的主题 爱
It's a good effort. It touched on one of the major themes: love.
不仅是诗歌的重大主题 也是生活的
A major theme not only in poetry but life.
霍普金斯 你在笑 你来吧
Mr Hopkins, you were laughing. You're up.
一只猫坐在垫子上
"The cat sat on the mat."
祝贺你 霍普金斯
Congratulations, Mr Hopkins.
按照普里查特的评分方法
Yours is the first poem to ever have a negative
你的诗是第一首得负分的
score on the Pritchard scale.
我们不是在笑你 是在恭喜你
We're not laughing at you, we're laughing near you.
我不在乎你的诗主题简单
I don't mind that your poem had a simple theme.
有时候最漂亮的诗主题也很简单
Sometimes the most beautiful poetry can be about simple things,
像一只猫 一朵花 一场雨
like a cat or a flower or rain.
知道吗 只要有新意 什么东西都可以写出诗来
You see, poetry can come from anything with the stuff of revelation in it.
只是不要让你的诗太俗套
Just don't let your poems be ordinary.
好了 谁下一位
Now, who's next?
安德森先生 你在那儿坐立不安
Mr Anderson, I see you sitting there in agony.
来吧 托德 站起来 让我们结束你的痛苦吧
Come on, Todd, step up. Let's put you out of your misery.
我... 我没做 我没写诗
I... I didn't do it. I didn't write a poem.
安德森认为自己内心的想法全都没有价值 都让人笑话
Mr Anderson thinks everything inside of him is worthless and embarrassing.
是这样吗 托德 这是你最担心的
Isn't that right, Todd? Isn't that your worst fear?
那么 你错了 我觉得你内心有些东西...
Well, I think you're wrong. I think you have something inside of you...
是很有价值的
that is worth a great deal.
我喊出...
"I sound...
我野性的...
"my barbaric...
狂叫
"yawp...
站在...
"over the rooftops...
世界的屋脊上
of the world."
又是惠特曼的诗
Uncle Walt, again.
好了 可能你们有些不知道 咆哮是一种大声的叫喊
Now, for those of you who don't know, a yawp is a loud cry or yell.
好了 托德 你给我们演示一下什么叫野性的咆哮
Now, Todd, I would like you to give us a demonstration of a barbaric yawp.
行了 你不会坐着咆哮
Come on, you can't yawp sitting down.
来吧 快点上去
Let's go. Come on, up.
好了 做好咆哮的姿势
Got to get in yawping stance.
- 咆哮  - 不仅仅是咆哮 野性的咆哮
- A... A yawp?  - Not just a yawp. A barbaric yawp.
- 好吧 咆哮  - 不行 大声点
- Right. Yawp.  - Come on. Louder.
- 咆哮  - 那是老鼠叫 来吧 大声点
- Yawp.  - That's a mouse. Come on, louder!
- 咆哮  - 天哪 叫得像个男人
- Yawp.  - Oh, good God, boy, yell like a man!
- 咆哮  - 这就对了
- Yawp!  - There it is.
你瞧 你身上到底也有野性
You see, you have a barbarian in you after all.
还不能这么就走 那是张惠特曼的照片
You don't get away that easy. There's a picture of Uncle Walt up there.
他让你想起谁 别想 回答 快点
What does he remind you of? Don't think, answer. Go on.
- 一个... 一个疯子  - 什么样的疯子
- A m-m-m-madman.  - What kind of madman?
- 不用想 只管回答  - 一个疯狂的疯子
- Don't think about it, just answer.  - A cr-crazy madman.
你可以答得更好 解放你的思想 发挥你的想象力
No, you can do better than that. Free up your mind. Use your imagination.
说出第一个跳进你脑子的东西 哪怕荒唐透顶
Say the first thing that pops into your head, even if it's total gibberish.
一... 一个牙齿流汗的疯子
A-A-A sweaty-toothed madman.
我的天哪 你还是有诗人气质嘛
Good God, boy, there's a poet in you after all!
好了 闭上眼睛 闭上眼睛
There. Close your eyes. Close your eyes. Close them.
好了 说你看到了什么
Now, describe what you see.
- 我闭上了眼睛...  - 还有呢
- Uh, I... I close my eyes...  - Yes?
- 他的形像在我眼前见  - 一个牙齿流汗的疯子
- uh, and his image floats beside me.  - A sweaty-toothed madman.
一个牙齿流汗的疯子瞪得我心嘭嘭直跳
A sweaty-toothed madman with a stare that pounds my brain.
哦 好极了
Oh, that's excellent!
让他动起来 让他做点什么
Now, give him action, make him do something.
他... 他伸出手掐我脖子
His hands reach out and choke me.
对了 好极了 好极了
That's it. Wonderful. Wonderful.
- 他一直在念叨  - 念叨什么
- And all the time he's mumbling.  - What's he mumbling?
- 念叨真理  - 对
- Mumbling truth.  - Yes.
真理就像一床总让你双脚冰凉的毯子
Truth is like a blanket that always leaves your feet cold.
别管他们 继续说毯子 继续说下去
Forget them. Forget them. Stay with the blanket. Tell me about that blanket.
你怎么扯 怎么拽 总也不够
Y-Y-You push it, stretch it, it'll never be enough.
踢也好 打也好 它总盖不住我们
You kick at it, beat it, it'll never cover any of us.
从我们哭着降生到我们奄奄一息
From the moment we enter crying to the moment we leave dying,
它只会盖住你的脸 不管你如何痛哭 如何叫喊
it'll just cover your face as you wail and cry and scream.
不要忘记了
Don't you forget this.
你太嫩了 皮茨
That a boy, Pittsie.
- 吸气 深一点  - 我爸收集了很多烟斗
- Inhale, deeply.  - My dad collects pipes.
- 真的  - 我爸至少有三十个
- Really?  - He must have 30.
你家里收集烟斗 真有意思
Your parents collect pipes? Oh, that's interesting.
诺克斯 来一口
Come on, Knox.Join in.
对 诺克斯 我们是政府派来的
Yeah, Knox, we're from the government.
来帮你的 有什么事吗
We're here to help. What's wrong?
- 是克里丝  - 是克里丝的照片 看
- It's Chris!  - Here's a picture of Chris for you!
- 把它放在你的烟管里抽了它  - 这没意思
- Put that in your pipe and smoke it.  - It's not funny.
别闹了 抽你们的烟吧
Knock it off. Smoke your pipes.
- 尼尔  - 朋友们 同学们 校友们
- Neil.  - Friends, scholars, Welton men.
那是什么 尼尔
What is that, Neil?
- 是盏灯 笨蛋  - 不 这是山洞之神
- Duh, it's a lamp, Meeks.  - No, this is the god of the cave.
山洞之神
The god of the cave.
- 查理 你在干什么  - 开始今天的会议日程吧
- Charlie, what are you doing?  - What do you say we start this meeting?
- 等等 我需要灯 谁带灯了  - 你带耳塞了吗
- I need a light. Who's got a light?  - Anybody bring earplugs?
各位
Gentlemen.
查尔斯・多尔顿的诗人音乐
"Poetrusic" by Charles Dalton.
欢笑 痛哭 跌倒 呓语
Laughing, crying, tumbling, mumbling.
必须做更多 必须是更多
Gotta do more, gotta be more.
混乱的叫喊 混乱的梦想 必须做更多 必须是更多
Chaos screaming, chaos dreaming. Gotta do more, gotta be more!
- 哇 太棒了  - 太棒了
- Wow. Nice.  - That was great.
你在哪儿学会的
Where did you learn to play like that?
我父母强迫我吹了好几年单簧管
My parents made me take the clarinet for years!
- 我喜欢单簧管  - 我恨透了
- I love the clarinet.  - I hated it.
萨克管 萨克管好听一些
The saxophone. The saxophone is more... sonorous.
更好听一些
Ooh, more sonorous. Vocabulary.
我再也受不了了 如果我得不到克里丝
I can't take it any more. If I don't have Chris,
- 我会自杀  - 诺克斯 你得冷静点儿
- I'm gonna kill myself.  - Knoxious, calm down.
不 查理 我的问题就在这儿
No, Charlie! That's just my problem.
我冷静了一辈子了 我得有所改变才行
I've been calm all my life. I'm gonna do something about that.
你去哪儿 你要干什么
Where are you going? What are you gonna do?
去给她打电话
I'm gonna call her.
- 他要给她打电话  - 等等我
- He's gonna call her!  - Wait for me!
喂
Hello?
她会恨我的
She's gonna hate me.
丹伯里全家都会恨我
The Danburrys will hate me.
我父母会杀了我
My parents will kill me.
好了 去他的吧
All right, goddam it.
没事的 卡匹迪恩
You're right. Carpe diem.
死又怎么样呢
Even if it kills me.
- 喂  - 喂 克里丝
- Hello?  - Hello, Chris?
- 是我  - 嗨 是诺克斯・奥弗斯特里特
- Yes.  - Hi. This is Knox Overstreet.
你好 诺克斯
Oh, yes. Knox.
- 很高兴你打电话来  - 她很高兴我打电话去
- I'm glad you called.  - She's glad I called.
听我说 切特的父母这个周末要出远门
Listen, Chet's parents are going out of town this weekend,
他想举行个晚会
and he's having a party.
- 你能过来吗  - 我能不能去参加晚会
- Would you like to come?  - Would I like to come to a party?
- 能 能  - 星期五晚上  - 没问题
- Yes. Say yes.  - It's Friday.  - Well, sure.
- 七点左右  - 好的 我会到的 克里丝
- About 7:00.  - Great. I'll be there, Chris.
- 太好了  - 星期五晚上 七点左右
- Okay.  - Friday night at the Danburrys'. Okay.
- 好 谢谢你  - 谢谢你 到时见 拜
- Okay. Bye.  - Thank you. I'll see you. Bye.
咆哮
Yawp!
你能相信吗
Can you believe it?
她本来就要给我打电话
She was gonna call me.
她还邀我和她参加晚会
She invited me to a party with her.
- 在切特・丹伯里家里  - 是
- At Chet Danburry's house.  - Yeah.
- 那  - 怎么啦
- Well?  - So?
那你不会真以为她是叫你陪她吧
So you don't really think she means you're going with her?
当然不是 查理 但关键不在那儿
Well, of course not, Charlie. But that's not the point.
- 关键根本不在那儿  - 关键在哪儿
- That's not the point at all.  - What is the point?
- 关键 查理...  - 呃...
- The point, Charlie...  - Uh-huh?
- 在...  - 嗯
- is...  - Yeah?
她在想着我
that she was thinking about me.
我只见过她一面
I've only met her once, and already...
而她真的在想着我
she's thinking about me.
没错 会发生的 伙计们
Damn it, it's gonna happen, guys.
我感觉到了
I feel it.
她会是我的
She is going to be mine.
卡匹迪恩
Carpe! Carpe!
跟学分没关系 各位 遛遛腿而已
No grades at stake, gentlemen. Just take a stroll.
开始吧
There it is.
我不知道 但有人对我说
I don't know, but I've been told.
写诗已经过时
Doing poetry is cold.
- 写诗已经过时  - 左 左 左 右 左
- Doing poetry is cold.  - Left. Left. Left, right, left.
左 左 左 右 左
Left. Left. Left, right, left.
左 停
Left. Halt!
谢谢各位
Thank you, gentlemen.
不知你们注意没有
If you noticed,
每个人开始都有自己的步伐 自己的节奏
everyone started off with their own stride, their own pace.
皮茨不着急 知道自己总有一天能到
Mr Pitts taking his time. He knew he'll get there one day.
卡梅伦呢 你能看出他在想
Mr Cameron. You could see him thinking,
"这对吗 可能是对的 我知道就是这样"
"Is this right? It might be right.
也许不是 我不知道
It might be right. I know that... Maybe not. I don't know."
奥弗斯特里特有一种更深的驱动力
Mr Overstreet, driven by a deeper force. Yes.
这我们知道 好了 我说这些并不是要嘲笑你们
We know that. All right. Now, I didn't bring them up here to ridicule them.
我说这些是为了说明顺从的问题
I brought them up here to illustrate the point of conformity.
说明坚持与众不同的信仰的困难
The difficulty in maintaining your own beliefs in the face of others.
你们有些人 你们的眼神好像在说
Now, I see the look in your eyes like,
"我本来可以走得不同"
"I would have walked differently."
那么问问自己刚才为什么拍手
Well, ask yourselves why you were clapping.
没错 我们都有一种被人接受的需要
Now we all have a great need for acceptance.
但是你们必须坚信自己的信仰是独特的 是你自己的
But you must trust that your beliefs are unique, your own.
哪怕别人认为它们很怪或者很讨厌
Even though others may think them odd or unpopular.
哪怕一群人都说"那太差了"
Even though the herd may go, "That's ba-a-a-a-ad."
罗伯特・弗罗斯特说过
Robert Frost said,
"两条路在树林中分岔 我选择走的人少那一条"
"Two roads diverged in the wood and I... I took the one less traveled by.
这就导致了所有的不同
And that has made all the difference."
现在 我希望你们也找到自己的路
I want you to find your own walk right now,
找到自己的步伐 步调 任何方向 任何东西都行
your own way of striding, pacing any direction.
不管自负也好 愚蠢也好 什么都行
Anything you want, whether it's proud, whether it's silly, anything.
各位 这个院子是你们的
Gentlemen, the courtyard is yours.
你们用不着表演 完全为你自己
You don't have to perform, just make it for yourself.
多尔顿 你不参加吗
Mr Dalton, will you be joining us?
在行使不走的权力
Exercising the right not to walk.
谢谢 多尔顿 要的就是这个劲儿
Thank you, Mr Dalton. Just illustrated the point.
敢于逆流而上
Swim against the stream.
托德
Todd?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
- 怎么啦  - 没事
- What's going on?  - Nothing.
- 今天是我生日  - 今天是你生日
- Today's my birthday.  - Is today your birthday?
- 生日快乐  - 谢谢
- Happy birthday.  - Thanks.
- 收到什么了  - 我爸妈给的
- What did you get?  - My parents just gave me this.
这不是一样的文具盒...
Isn't this the same desk set...
对 跟去年送的一模一样
Yeah, yeah, they gave me the same thing as last year.
可能他们觉得你需要换一个了
Maybe they thought you needed another one.
可能他们什么也没想
Maybe they weren't thinking about anything at all.
好笑的是 我第一次就不喜欢
The funny thing is, about this, is I didn't even like it the first time.
托德 我看你低估这文具盒的价值了
Todd, I think you're underestimating the value of this desk set.
我是说 谁会想要一个足球或者棒球呢
I mean, who would want a football or a baseball...
- 或者一辆车  - 或者一辆车
- Or a car.  - Mm-hmm, or a car
如果他们能得到这么漂亮一个文具盒的话
if they could have a desk set as wonderful as this one.
我是说 如果我要买一个文具盒... 两次
I mean, if I were ever going to buy a desk set... twice,
我很可能会买这种... 两次都是
I would probably buy this one... both times.
实际上 它看上去...
In fact, its... shape is...
很有点流线形的味道 对不对
It's rather aerodynamic, isn't it?
能摸得出来
You can feel it.
这文具盒想飞
This desk set wants to fly.
托德...
Todd...
世界上第一个无人驾驶飞行文具盒
the world's first unmanned flying desk set.
哦 天哪 不用担心
Oh, my! Well, I wouldn't worry.
你明年还会收到一个的
You'll get another one next year.
活得深刻 吸取生命中所有的精华
"To live deep and suck out all the marrow of life.
把非生命的一切都击溃
To put to rout all that was not life..."
天哪
My God.
- 就是这  - 对 就是这
- Is this it?  - Yeah, this is it.
进去吧 是我的山洞 当心脚底下
Go ahead. Go on in. It's my cave. Watch your step.
嗨
Hi.
- 你们好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hi.
伙计们 介绍一下 格洛丽亚和...
Hi, guys. Meet, uh, Gloria and...
- 蒂娜  - 蒂娜
- Tina.  - Tina.
他们在念死亡诗人俱乐部的誓词
This is the pledge class of the Dead Poets Society.
- 你好  - 你好
- How do you do?  - Hello.
伙计们 继续 继续 来吧
Guys, move. Move! Come on,
伙计们 今天星期五
folks, it's Friday night.
聚会现在开始 各位 我要宣布一件事
Let's get on with the meeting. Guys, I have an announcement to make.
为了实践死亡诗人义无反顾的开拓精神
In keeping with the spirit of passionate experimentation of the Dead Poets,
我决定放弃查理・多尔顿这个名字
I'm giving up the name Charles Dalton.
从现在起 叫我纽旺达
From now on, call me Nuwanda.
纽旺达
Nuwanda?
你好 你好 克里丝
Hello? Hello, Chris?
I crashed in thejungle while trying to keep a date
With my little girl who was back in the States
I was stranded in thejungle...
- 你好  - 你来了 太好了
- Hi.  - You made it! Great.
- 你带人来了吗  - 没有
- Did you bring anybody?  - No.
没有 吉尼・丹伯里来了 听我说 我得去找切特
No? Ginny Danburry's here. Look, I have to go find Chet.
你干嘛不到楼下去 客人全在那儿
Why don't you go downstairs? That's where everybody is.
但克里丝 我...
Yeah, but Chris, I've...
- 随便一点  - 但是我...
- Make yourself at home.  - But I've...
Baby baby let's make romance
You know your old-time lover hasn't got a chance
嘿 你是马特・桑德斯的弟弟
Hey, you Mutt Sanders' brother?
巴布 你看他像马特・桑德斯的弟弟吗
Bubba, this guy look like Mutt Sanders to you, or what?
- 你是他弟弟  - 没关系
- You're his brother?  - No relation.
- 没听说过 抱歉  - 礼貌到哪去了 史蒂夫
- Never heard of him. Sorry, guys.  - Where's our manners, Steve?
这位是马特・桑德斯的弟弟 还不请他喝一杯
Here's Mutt Sanders' brother and we don't even offer him a drink.
- 给你 来点威士忌 伙计  - 好吧
- Here you go. Have some whisky, pal.  - Yeah.
我... 我不喝威士忌
I, uh, I don't really drink whisky.
- 敬马特  - 敬马特
- To Mutt.  - To Mutt.
敬马特
To Mutt.
- 你哥跑哪去了  - 你哥干嘛去了
- How the hell is old Mutt anyway?  - Yeah, what's old Mutter been up to?
真的 我不认识马特
I don't really know Mutt.
敬伟大的马特
To the Mighty Mutt.
- 敬伟大的马特  - 敬伟大的马特
- To Mighty Mutt.  - To Mighty Mutt.
好了 听着 我得去找帕齐了
Listen, I gotta go find Patsy.
- 代我向马特问好 行吗  - 好的
- Say hello to Mutt for me, okay?  - Will do.
是个人物 你哥马特
Hell of a guy, your brother Mutt.
会还开不开
We gonna have a meeting, or what?
对呀 你们不开会
Yeah, if you guys don't have a meeting,
我们怎么知道想不想加入呢
how do we know if we want to join?
加入
"Join"?
我该把你比做美丽的夏日
"Shall I compare thee to a summer's day?
你比夏日更可爱 更温柔
Thou art more lovely and more temperate."
太美了
That's so sweet.
- 是我写的 送给你  - 你写的
- I made that up just for you.  - You did?
我也给你写了一首 格洛丽亚
I'll write one for you too, Gloria.
她在黑夜款款而行
"She walks in beauty like the night.
"She walks in beauty like the night...
星光闪烁的天空朗朗无云
"of cloudless climes and starry skies.
黑夜和白昼的所有美丽
"All that's best, dark and bright,
- 都在她的身影和眼睛中汇集  - 太美了
- meet in her aspect and her eyes."  - That's beautiful.
我还有很多这样的诗
There's plenty more where that came from.
She sure looks fine to me What's her name
Look out Let me call her one time
Hey little girl
Gee you sure look fine
救救我
God, help me.
Ooh baby you're not mine
Hey little girl How's about a date
卡匹迪恩
Carpe diem.
How's about a date
You know I'll come get you early baby
Won't keep you out too late
Say little girl
Now how's about a kiss
Yeah say little girl
How's about a kiss
Well if you don't kiss me baby
- 切特 切特 快看  - 什么
- Chet. Chet. Look.  - What?
是马特・桑德斯的弟弟
It's Mutt Sanders' brother.
- 诺克斯...  - 怎么他占你女朋友便宜
- Knox, what...  - And he's feeling up your girl!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
- 你他妈在干嘛  - 切特 别这样
- What the hell are you doing?  - Chet. Chet, don't!
- 听我说 切特 我知道这不好...  - 别管他了
- Now, Chet, I know this looks bad...  - Leave him alone.
切特 不 会打伤他的
Chet, no! You'll hurt him!
- 不 求你了 快住手  - 妈的
- Chet, stop it! Leave him alone!  - Damn!
- 切特 别打了 住手  - 他妈的
- Chet, stop it!  - Bastard!
诺克斯 你没事吧
Knox, are you all right?
克里丝 别他妈理他
Chris, get the hell away from him!
- 切特 你伤他了  - 太好了
- Chet, you hurt him!  - Good!
- 对不起 真对不起  - 没关系 这... 这没关系
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.  - It's okay. It's... It's okay.
再见到你 要你小命
Next time I see you, you die.
喝吧 都喝点儿
Go ahead. Pass it around.
我和皮茨在做一套音响
Me and Pitts are working on a hi-fi system.
并不难做
It shouldn't be that hard to, uh, to put together.
我可能会上耶鲁大学
Yeah. Uh, I might be going to Yale.
但... 也可能不上
Uh, but I... I might not.
你们不想叫女孩上这儿来吗
Don't you guys miss having girls around here?
- 想啊  - 想啊
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
这也是俱乐部的目标之一
That's part of what this club is about.
实际上 我要告诉各位...
In fact, I'd like to announce...
我以死亡诗人的名义在校报上登了篇文章
I published an article in the school paper in the name of the Dead Poets,
- 什么  - 要求学校接收女生
- What?  - demanding girls be admitted to Welton...
- 不会吧  - 所以我们都可以停止躁动了
- You didn't.  - so we can all stop beating off.
- 怎么可能呢  - 我是校对之一
- How did you do that?  - I'm one of the proofers.
- 我把文章塞了进去  - 这... 这下完了
- I slipped the article in.  - It's... It's over now.
为什么 没人知道是谁
Why? Nobody knows who we are.
但你不觉得他们会猜出来是谁写的吗
Well, don't you think they're gonna figure out who wrote it?
他们会找到你 问你死亡诗人俱乐部是怎么回事
They're gonna come to you and ask to know what the Dead Poets Society is.
查理 你没有权力这么胡来
Charlie, you had no right to do something like that.
我叫纽旺达 卡梅伦
It's Nuwanda, Cameron.
没错 叫纽旺达
That's right. It's Nuwanda.
我们是跑这儿来玩呢 还是真要干点什么
Are we just playing around out here, or do we mean what we say?
如果我们只是凑到一起念几首诗
If all we do is come together and read a bunch of poems to each other,
- 我们到这儿干嘛  - 好了
- what the hell are we doing?  - All right.
但你还是不应该这么做 查理
But you still shouldn't have done it, Charlie.
这会惹来麻烦的 你不能代表俱乐部
This could mean trouble. You don't speak for the club.
嘿 你们别那么胆小 行不行
Hey, would you not worry about your precious little neck?
如果他们找到我 我就说是我瞎编的
If they catch me, I'll tell them I made it up.
好
Fine.
请坐
Sit.
在本周的校报上
In this week's issue of Welton Honor,
出现了一篇私自添加的不堪入目的文章
there appeared a profane and unauthorized article.
我不想浪费我宝贵的时间去追查
Rather than spend my valuable time ferreting out the guilty persons...
但我保证我一定会查出来
and let me assure you I will find them...
我希望任何一位知道这篇文章的情况的同学
I'm asking any and all students who know anything about this article...
现在就站出来说清楚
to make themselves known here and now.
不管是谁干的
Whoever the guilty persons are,
这是你避免被学校开除的唯一机会
this is your only chance to avoid expulsion from this school.
威尔顿中学 你好
Welton Academy. Hello.
是 他在 请等一下
Yes, he is. just a moment.
诺兰先生 找你的
Mr Nolan, it's for you.
上帝打来的
It's God!
他说威尔顿中学应该有女生
He says we should have girls at Welton.
别瞎得意了
Wipe that smirk off your face.
如果你觉得 多尔顿
If you think, Mr Dalton,
你是第一个想被学校开除的人 你错了
that you're the first to try to get thrown out of this school, think again.
其他人也有过这种想法
Others have had similar notions
但他们想错了 就像你一样
and have failed just as surely as you will fail.
摆好姿势
Assume the position.
大声数 多尔顿
Count aloud, Mr Dalton.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
五
Five.
什么叫死亡诗人俱乐部 告诉我名字
What is this Dead Poets Society? I want names.
- 被开除了  - 不
- You kicked out?  - No.
那怎么回事
So what happened?
让我把所有人供出来 向全校道歉
I'm to turn everybody in, apologise to the school,
然后大家都没事
and all will be forgiven.
那你准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
- 查理  - 见鬼 尼尔
- Charlie...  - Damn it, Neil,
我叫纽旺达
the name is Nuwanda.
对不起 能谈谈吗 基丁老师
Excuse me. May we have a word, Mr Keating?
可以
Certainly.
这是我上课的第一间教室 你知道吗
This was my first classroom, John. Did you know that?
第一张讲台
My first desk.
不知道你还教过课 诺兰先生
I didn't know you taught, Mr Nolan.
教英语 比你早多了
English. Long before your time.
不教还真舍不得 说老实话
It was hard giving it up, I can tell you.
我听传言说
I'm hearing rumours
你在你班上用的一些非正统的教学方法
about some unorthodox teaching methods in your classroom.
我不是说这跟那个叫多尔顿的学生的错误有关
I'm not saying they've had anything to do with the Dalton boy's outburst,
但我想我用不着提醒你
but I don't think I have to warn you boys
他这种年龄的孩子很容易受人影响
his age are very impressionable.
你的惩罚对他很有影响 我肯定
Well, your reprimand made quite an impression, I'm sure.
- 那天在院子里是怎么回事  - 院子
- What was going on in the courtyard the other day?  - Courtyard?
- 孩子们一起走 一起拍手  - 那个...
- Boys marching, clapping in unison.  - Oh, that.
那是为了证明一个观点 顺从的危险
That was an exercise to prove a point: dangers of conformity.
约翰 这儿的课程是固定的 已经过检验并很有效
Well, John, the curriculum here is set. It's proven. It works.
如果你有疑问 也不该随随便便乱改
If you question it, what's to prevent them from doing the same?
我始终认为教育的根本在于学会自我思考
I always thought the idea of education was to learn to think for yourself.
在他们这种年纪 开玩笑
At these boys' age? Not on your life!
传统 纪律
Tradition, John. Discipline.
送他们上大学 其余的就不用管了
Prepare them for college, and the rest will take care of itself.
他当时正朝我左边绕过来
He starts walking around towards my left.
摆好姿势 多尔顿 也就是说...
'Assume the position, Mr Dalton, " which means...
你们好 各位
All right, gentlemen.
- 基丁老师  - 多尔顿
- Mr Keating.  - Mr Dalton.
你今天的表演很拙劣
That was a pretty lame stunt you pulled today.
你跟诺兰老师站一边
You're siding with Mr Nolan?
那卡匹迪恩和吸取生命中所有精华
What about carpe diem and sucking all the marrow...
- 是怎么回事  - 吸取生命中所有精华...
- out of life and all that?  - Sucking the marrow out of life...
不是叫你胡来
doesn't mean choking on the bone.
有时候要大胆 有时候要小心
There is a time for daring, and there is a time for caution.
一个聪明人知道什么时候该怎么做
And a wise man understands which is called for.
我还以为你会喜欢呢
But I thought you'd like that.
不
No.
在我看来 被学校开除不是勇敢 是愚蠢
You being expelled from school is not daring to me. It's stupid.
因为你会失去很多大好的机会
'Cause you'll miss some golden opportunities.
是吗 比方说
Yeah? Like what?
比方 不说别的 听我的课的机会
Like, if nothing else, the opportunity to attend my classes.
明白了 英雄
Got it, ace?
唉 船长
Aye, aye, Captain.
做事用点脑子
Keep your head about you.
你们也都一样
That goes for the lot of you.
- 是 船长  - 是 船长
- Yes, Captain.  - Yes, Captain.
上帝来电话
Phone call from God.
如果由受话人付款就称得上勇敢了
If it'd been collect, it would have been daring.
- 好吧 继续  - 不
- All right. Go on, boy.  - No.
我们练习一遍 好吗 开始
We're trying to rehearse, okay? Go.
我有个想法 所以请听我说 赫米亚
A good persuasion, therefore hear me, Hermia.
我感觉不到任何的激情 我没有听到任何一句有激情的话
Wait, wait. The excitement. I don't hear any excitement about this play.
拉住她的手 领她下来
Now take her hand, bring her downstage...
然后说 "美丽 温柔的赫米亚"
and stop and "Fair, gentle Hermia."
行吗 试一下
Okay? Try again.
晚饭吃什么
What's for dinner?
- 空心粉和肉丸子  - 吃饭啦
- Spaghetti and meatballs!  - Food!
给我留点儿
Save some for me.
快走 小仙女 奥伯伦来了
"But, room, fairy! Here comes Oberon."
- 爸爸  - 尼尔
- Father.  - Neil.
等一下 您先别说...
Wait a minute. Before you say anything,
- 请听我解释...  - 你居然敢跟我顶嘴
- please let me ex...  - Don't you dare talk back to me.
你浪费时间去演什么破戏...
It's bad enough that you've wasted your time...
已经够意思了
with this, this absurd acting business,
但你居然故意欺骗我
but you deliberately deceived me.
你以为能逃脱得了
How... How... How did you expect to get away with this?
回答我
Answer me.
谁唆使你干的
Who put you up to it?
- 是那个新来的老师 叫基丁的  - 不
- Was it this new man? Keating?  - No.
没人唆使 我只是想给你个惊喜
Nobody p... I thought I'd surprise you.
我每门课都得了A
I've gotten all A's in every class.
你真以为我发现不了
Did you really think I wasn't going to find out?
马克斯夫人说 "我侄女和你儿子在演一出戏"
"Oh, my niece is in a play with your son," says Mrs Marks.
"不 不 不" 我说
"No, no, no," I say.
"你肯定搞错了 我儿子没在演戏"
"You must be mistaken. My son's not in a play."
你让我成了个骗子 尼尔
You made a liar out of me, Neil!
好了 明天你去找他们 告诉他们你不演了
Now, tomorrow, you go to them and you tell them that you're quitting.
不 不行
No, I can't.
我演的是主角 明天晚上就上演
I have the main part. The performance is tomorrow night!
就是世界明天晚上毁灭 我也不管
I don't care if the world comes to an end tomorrow night,
那戏你不能去演
you are through with that play!
明白了吗
Is that clear?
明白了
Yes, sir.
我付出了很大的牺牲才把你弄到这儿来
I made a great many sacrifices to get you here, Neil,
你不能让我失望
and you will not let me down.
知道
No, sir.
门开着
It's open.
尼尔 怎么啦
Neil, what's up?
- 我能和你谈谈吗  - 当然 坐吧
- Can I speak to you a minute?  - Certainly. Sit down.
- 对不起 给你  - 很抱歉
- I'm sorry. Here.  - Excuse me.
- 喝杯茶  - 茶 好的
- Get you some tea?  - Tea? Sure.
- 要加点奶或者糖吗  - 不用 谢谢
- Want some milk or sugar in that?  - No, thanks.
他们给你的房间够小的
Gosh, they don't give you much room around here.
修行生活的一部分
It's part of the monastic oath.
他们不想让世俗的东西让我分神
They don't want worldly things distracting me from my teaching.
- 她很漂亮  - 她也在伦敦
- She's pretty.  - She's also in London.
所以有些不方便
Makes it a little difficult.
- 你怎么忍受得了  - 忍受什么
- How do you stand it?  - Stand what?
你哪儿都可以去 什么都可以做
You can go anywhere. You can do anything.
你怎么能忍受呆在这儿呢
How can you stand being here?
因为我喜欢教书 我不想去其他地方
Because I love teaching. I don't want to be anywhere else.
- 怎么了  - 我刚和我父亲谈过
- What's up?  - I just talked to my father.
他要我退出那场戏的演出
He's making me quit the play at Henley Hall.
但演戏对我很重要
But acting is everything to me.
我是说... 但他不知道...
I mean... But he doesn't know. He...
我明白他的意思 我们家不富裕
I can see his point. We're not a rich family
不像查理 我是说...
like Charlie's. I mean...
但他想替我安排我的将来
But he's planning the rest of my life for me.
他从来不问我想什么
And he... he's never asked me what I want.
你跟你父亲说过你刚跟我说的话吗
Have you ever told your father what you just told me?
你对戏剧的热爱 告诉过他吗
About your passion for acting? Have you showed him that?
- 我做不到  - 为什么
- I can't.  - Why not?
我不能这么跟他说话
I can't talk to him this way.
那你在他面前也在表演
Then you're acting for him too.
演一个听话的儿子的角色
You're playing the part of the dutiful son.
我知道这听起来好像不可能 但你必须跟他谈
I know this sounds impossible, but you have to talk to him.
必须让他明白你是什么人 你的心在哪儿
You have to show him who you are, what your heart is.
我知道他会说什么
I know what he'll say.
他会说演戏是一时心血来潮 我不要再想了
He'll tell me that acting's a whim and I should forget it.
说他们就指望我了
They're counting on me.
告诉我不要再想这些了 为了我自己好
He'll just tell me to put it out of my mind for my own good.
你又不是个雇来的仆人
You are not an indentured servant.
那不是你心血来潮
It's not a whim for you.
用你的坚定和激情向他证明这一点
You prove it to him by your conviction and your passion.
让他明白这一点 如果他还不相信你...
You show him that, and if he still doesn't believe you...
那时候你也毕业了 想干什么都可以了
Well, by then, you'll be out of school, and you can do anything you want.
不
No.
那这戏怎么办 明晚就要上演
What about the play? The show's tomorrow night.
那你就得在明晚之前跟他谈
Then you have to talk to him before tomorrow night.
我...
I...
- 我有没有容易点儿的办法  - 没有
- Isn't there an easier way?  - No.
我走投无路了
I'm trapped.
不 你不是
No, you're not.
克里丝
Chris!
克里丝・诺埃尔 你知道她在哪儿吗
Chris! Chris Noel. Do you know where she is?
- 好像在111号房间  - 谢谢
- Um, I think she's in Room 111.  - Thanks.
我知道了
I know.
对不起 克里斯...
Excuse me. Chris...
诺克斯 你到这儿来干嘛
Knox, what are you doing here?
来为那晚的事道歉
I came to apologize for the other night.
这送给你 我还给你写了首诗
I brought you these and a poem I wrote for you.
诺克斯 你不知道如果切特发现你在这儿
Knox, don't you know that if Chet finds you here,
他会杀了你吗
he'll kill you?
- 我不管 我爱你 克里丝  - 诺克斯 你疯了
- I don't care. I love you, Chris.  - Knox, you're crazy.
听我说 我表现得像个傻瓜 我知道
Look, I acted like a jerk, and I know it.
- 请你接受 求你了  - 不 不 我... 我不能
- Please accept these. Please.  - No. No, I... I can't.
别这样
Just forget it.
- 诺克斯 我不相信  - 我不求别的 只要你听
- Knox, I don't believe this.  - All I'm asking you to do is listen.
上帝的杰作 女孩克里丝...
"The heavens made a girl named Chris...
肌肤如雪 金发如丝
"with hair and skin of gold.
伸手可触...
"To touch her...
已是幸福的极致
would be paradise."
滚出去 卡梅伦 你个笨蛋
Get out of here. Cameron, you fool.
怎么样 念给她听了吗
Hey, how'd it go? Did you read it to her?
- 是  - 她说什么
- Yeah.  - Wow. What'd she say?
- 没说  - 没说是什么意思
- Nothing.  - What do you mean, nothing?
没说 但我做了
Nothing. But I did it.
她说什么 她肯定得说点什么
Well, what did she say? She had to say something!
- 嘿 诺克斯  - 抓紧时间
- Hey, Knox!  - Seize the day!
- 跟你父亲谈了吗  - 谈了
- Did you talk to your father?  - Uh, yeah.
他很不高兴 但至少他让我把戏演完了
He didn't like it one bit, but at least he's letting me stay in the play.
他不能来看演出 他在芝加哥
He won't be able to m-make it. He's in Chicago.
但是我想他会让我演下去的
But, uh, I think he's gonna let me stay with acting.
是吗 你把昨天的话跟他说了
Really? You told him what you told me?
嗯
Yeah.
他不高兴
He wasn't happy.
但他要出门至少四天
But he'll be gone at least four days.
我想他不能来看戏 但...
I don't think he'll make the show, but...
但我想他会让我演下去的
I think he'll let me stay with it.
别拉下功课
"Keep up the schoolwork."
谢谢
Thanks.
- 哦 宝贝  - 漂亮宝贝
- Oh, baby.  - Beautiful baby.
- 我...  - 对不起
- I am...  - Excuse me.
马上就好 嗯 很帅嘛
Just a moment. Yes. You're so good.
别闹 托德 好不容易梳好
Come on, Todd. I'm trying to fix this.
快点 纽旺达 不然看不到尼尔上场了
Come on, Nuwanda, we're going to miss Neil's entrance.
他说什么走之前要我们弄红点儿
He said something about getting red before we left.
- 弄红点儿 这是什么意思  - 谁知道 你知道查理
- "Getting red"? What does that mean?  - I... You know Charlie.
查理 弄红点儿是怎么回事
So, Charlie, what's this 'getting red"bit?
那是什么
What is that?
印地安武士雄性的象征
It's an Indian warrior symbol for virility.
让我觉得很来劲儿 能让女孩们发疯
Makes me feel potent, like I can drive girls crazy.
快点 查理 女孩们等着呢
Oh, come on, Charlie. The girls are waiting.
哇哦
Whoa.
克里丝
Chris.
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
- 先生们 走吧  - 你们先走吧 我马上来
- Gentlemen, let's go!  - Go ahead, guys. I'll catch up.
好 走吧 伙计们
Yeah. Come on, guys.
你不能呆在这儿
Chris, you can't be in here.
- 如果让他们发现 我们俩麻烦就大了  - 拜托...
- If they catch you, we're both gonna be in big trouble.  - Come on.
- 那你...  - 嘘 嘘 克里丝
- Oh, but it's fine if...  - Shh, shh. Chris.
那你跑到我学校去让我那么难堪就好啦
It's fine for you to come barging into my school and make a fool out of me?
我没想让你难堪
I didn't mean to make a fool out of you.
结果是那样 切特知道了
Well, you did. Chet found out.
我费了很大劲儿才没让他到这儿来杀了你
It took everything I could do to keep him from coming here and killing you.
诺克斯 你以后别干这种傻事了
Knox, you have got to stop this stuff.
我做不到 克里丝 我爱你
I can't, Chris. I love you.
诺克斯 这话说了很多遍了
Knox, you say that over and over.
你根本还不了解我呢
You don't... You don't even know me.
你们上车吗 奥弗斯特里特
Will you bejoining us, Mr Overstreet?
你们走吧 我走过去
Go ahead, Captain. I'll walk.
诺克斯 诺克斯 如果我...
Knox. Knox, it just so happens...
根本就不喜欢你呢
that I could care less about you.
那你就不会到这儿来提醒我当心切特
Then you wouldn't be here warning me about Chet.
我得走了 看戏要迟到了
I have to go. I'm gonna be late for the play.
- 跟他一起去  - 切特 去看戏
- Are you going with him?  - Chet? To a play?
- 你开玩笑吧  - 那就跟我去吧
- Are you kidding?  - Then come with me.
诺克斯 你怎么这么烦人哪
Knox, you are so infuriating!
好啦 克里丝 就给我一次机会
Come on, Chris, just give me one chance.
如果过了今晚你不喜欢我 我绝不再打扰你
If you don't like me after tonight, I'll stay away forever.
我以死亡诗人的名义保证
I promise. Dead Poets honour.
你今晚跟我去
You come with me tonight,
然后如果你不想再见到我 我发誓我会退出
and then if you don't want to see me again, I swear I'll bow out.
- 如果切特知道了 会发生什么吗  - 他不会知道的
- What would happen if Chet found out?  - He won't know anything.
我们坐在后面 戏一完就溜出来
We'll sit in the back and sneak away as soon as it's over.
你真的保证这是最后一次
And I suppose you would promise that this would be the end of it?
- 以死亡诗人的名义  - 这是什么意思
- Dead Poets honour.  - What is that?
- 誓词  - 嗯
- My word.  - Hmm.
你真的很讨厌
You are so infuriating.
嘿 他出来了
Hey, there he is! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
嘘 同学们
Shh, boys.
要是我没看错的话...
Either I mistake your shape and making quite...
你就是那个名叫罗宾・古德费洛的机灵狡猾的捣蛋鬼
or else you are that shrewd and knavish sprite called Robin Goodfellow!
你说对了
Thou speak'st aright.
我就是那个快乐的夜游人
I am that merry wanderer of the night.
我跟奥伯伦开玩笑逗他开心
I jest to Oberon and make him smile...
我装成一匹高大的马
when I a fat and bean-fed horse beguile.
却学小母马叫
Neighing in the likeness of a filly foal.
有时候我躲在大酒杯里
Sometime lurk I in a gossip's bowl...
装成一只烤熟的螃蟹
in very likeness of a roasted crab.
她端起酒杯 我就窜到她嘴上
And when she drink, against her lips I bob...
吓得她把酒灌进脖子里
and on her withered dewlap pour the ale.
- 闹她个大笑话  - 演得好 演得真好
- The wisest aunt telling the saddest tale.  - He's good. He's really good.
有时候我装成一条三足凳
Sometime for three-foot stool mistaketh me.
然后从她屁股底下溜走 弄得她一屁股摔倒
Then slip I from her bum, down topples she and "Tailor" cries...
不停地咳嗽
and falls into a cough.
然后所有人都捧腹大笑
And then the whole quire hold their hips and laugh...
笑得前仰后合
and waxen in their mirth nee-e-e-eze...
说...
and swear.
从没有过这么开心的时候
A merrier hour was never wasted there.
快走 小仙女
But, room, fairy.
是奥伯伦 他来了
Here comes Oberon.
还有小妞 来得真不是时候
And here, my mistress. Would that he were gone.
只要能躺在你身边 再好的卧室也不能让我离开
Then by your side, no bed-room me deny.
我没有说谎 赫米亚
For lying so, Hermia, I do not lie.
我没有说你说谎
Lysander riddles very prettily. Much beshrew my manners...
那样的话我也太失敬爱和礼貌了
and my pride if Hermia meant to say Lysander lied.
不过 我的朋友 出于敬爱和礼节
But, gentle friend, for love and courtesy...
请躺远一点 按礼敬的标准
lie further off, in human modesty,
这样的距离才适合一对品行纯洁的单身男子和姑娘
such separation as may well be said becomes a virtuous bachelor and maid.
晚安 亲爱的朋友 愿你的爱终身不渝
Good night, sweet friend. Thy love ne'er alter 'til thy sweet life end.
阿门 愿你的祈祷成真
Amen. Amen to that fair prayer, say I.
我结束了忠诚也就结束了生命
And then end life when I end loyalty.
尼尔 该你上了 尼尔
Neil. That's your cue, Neil.
快点 尼尔 你的帽子 走吧
Come on, Neil. Here's your crown. Let's go.
如果我们的出现冒犯了各位...
If we shadows have offended...
请原谅我们的过失
think but this and all is mended.
就当我们出现的时候 你们在这儿睡了一觉
That you have but slumber'd here while these visions did appear.
这场小小的闹剧只不过是一场梦境
And this weak and idle theme, no more yielding but a dream.
各位 请不要过于怪罪
Gentles, do not reprehend.
如果允许 我们会悔过
If you pardon, we will mend.
我是一个诚实的小鬼 如果我们有幸逃过惩罚
And as I am an honest Puck, if we have unearned luck,
我们会很快改过自新
now to 'scape the serpent's tongue,
不然你就叫我是个骗子
we will make amends ere long; else the Puck a liar call.
好了 祝各位晚安
So, good night unto you all.
请把手伸给我 如果我们是朋友
Give me your hands if we be friends,
再次请求你们的宽怨
and Robin shall restore amends.
卡匹迪恩
Yawp! Carpe diem!
太棒了
That was great!
我是尼尔的父亲 我想见见他 行吗
Excuse me. I'm Neil's father. I'd like to see him, please.
尼尔 你爸找你
Neil, your father.
- 你认为怎样  - 你的表演真实太精彩了
- What did you think?  - You were all just wonderful!
对不起 请让一下
Excuse me, please.
- 对不起 请让一下  - 尼尔 过来
- Excuse me. Excuse me.  - Neil! Back here! Neil!
尼尔 尼尔 太棒了 回去吧 尼尔
Neil, Neil, you were great! Come back, Neil.
- 不行 伙计们  - 尼尔
- I can't, guys.  - Neil.
对不起
Excuse me.
尼尔 你有这个天才
Neil. Neil. You have the gift.
演得真好 我都看呆了
What a performance. You left even me speechless.
- 你一定要坚持...  - 上车吧
- You have to stay with...  - Get in the car.
基丁 离我儿子远点儿
Keating, you stay away from my son.
尼尔 佩里先生 求你了
Neil! Neil! Mr Perry, come on!
别把事情越弄越糟
Don't make it any worse than it is.
你想做另一辆车吗
Do you want to take the other car?
我们走回去行吗
Is it okay if we walk back?
船长
Captain?
- 诺克斯  - 什么
- Knox?  - What?
我们11:30的时候就会到家
We'll be home about 11:30.
我们一直在想你为什么
We're trying very hard...
偏偏要违背我们的意思
to understand why it is that you insist on defying us.
但不管是什么原因 我们不会让你毁了自己一生
But whatever the reason, we're not gonna let you ruin your life.
明天我就让你从这个学校退学 上布莱登军校
I'm withdrawing you from Welton and enrolling you in Braden Military School.
你要上哈佛 你要成为一个医生
You're going to Harvard, and you're gonna be a doctor.
那还要十年
But that's ten more years.
- 爸爸 那太漫长了  - 闭嘴
- Father, that's a lifetime!  - Oh, stop it!
别夸张了 听上去像关你监狱似的
Don't be so dramatic. You make it sound like a prison term.
你不明白 尼尔
You don't understand, Neil.
你有很好的机会 我做梦都没想过的好机会
You have opportunities that I never even dreamt of!
- 我不会让你错过  - 我要告诉你我是什么感觉
- I am not going to let you waste them!  - I've got to tell you what I feel.
我们很担心 要是...
We've been so worried about...
什么 告诉我你的感觉
What? What? Tell me what you feel!
什么感觉
What is it?
是不是又是演戏这回事
Is it more of this-this acting business?
你就别想了
Because you can forget that.
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
Nothing?
那好 那就睡觉吧
Well, then, let's go to bed.
我演得很好 真的很好
I was good. I was really good.
好了 睡觉吧
Go on, get some sleep.
没事的 会没事的
It's going to be all right.
怎么回事
What was that?
什么
What?
- 那声音  - 什么声音
- That sound.  - What sound?
汤姆
Tom?
怎么啦
What is it?
出什么事啦
What's wrong?
尼尔
Neil?
汤姆 怎么啦
Tom, what is it?
出什么事了
What's wrong?
尼尔
Neil?
- 尼尔  - 我到外面看看
- Neil?  - I'll look outside.
尼尔
Neil?
不
No!
- 尼尔 哦 天哪  - 哦 天哪
- Oh, Neil! Oh, my God!  - Oh, my God. Oh, no, no.
- 我的孩子 我可怜的孩子  - 不 他没事
- Oh, my son! My son! My poor son!  - He's all right.
- 他没事  - 好啦 好啦
- He's all right!  - Stop it. Stop it. Stop it.
好啦 好啦
Stop it! Stop it.
托德
Todd. Todd.
查理
Oh, Charlie.
怎么啦
What is it?
尼尔死了
Neil's dead.
真漂亮
It's so beautiful.
托德
Todd!
- 别这样 托德  - 冷静点
- It's okay, Todd.  - Calm down.
好啦 托德
It's all right, Todd.
- 托德 别这样  - 别这样 托德
- Todd, it's okay.  - It's okay, Todd.
好啦 会没事的
It's all right. It's all right.
- 他本不会这么做的  - 这没法解释 托德
- He wouldn't have done it.  - You can't explain it, Todd.
- 是他父亲  - 不
- It was his father!  - No!
他本不会离开我们的 是因为...
He wouldn't have left us. It's because he...
他本不会的
He wouldn't have.
- 他的死...  - 托德
- His dad was...  - Todd.
是他父亲逼的 他父亲杀了他
His-His father did it. His father killed him.
他父亲杀了他
He made him do it.
托德
Todd!
让他静静吧
Leave him be.
... All my life
Shall surely
Follow me
And in God's house
Forevermore
My dwelling place
Shall be
Amen
尼尔・佩里的死是场悲剧
The death of Neil Perry is a tragedy.
他本是个好学生
He was a fine student,
本校最好的学生之一
one of Welton's best.
我们会怀念他的
And he will be missed.
我们已和所有的家长联系过解释这件事
We've contacted each of your parents to explain the situation.
当然 他们都很关注
Naturally, they're all quite concerned.
根据尼尔家人的请求
At the request of Neil's family,
我打算深入调查这件事
I intend to conduct a thorough inquiry into this matter.
希望你们全都合作
Your complete cooperation is expected.
- 你跟他说聚会的事了吗  - 两次
- You told him about this meeting?  - Twice.
伙计们 看来我们全被卖了
That's it, guys. We're all fried.
- 你什么意思  - 卡梅伦是个叛徒
- How do you mean?  - Cameron's a fink.
- 他现在就在诺兰办公室告密  - 告什么
- He's in Nolan's office now, finking.  - About what?
俱乐部 皮茨 想想吧
The club, Pittsie. Think about it.
校董会 评议员 还有诺兰老师
The board of directors, the trustees and Mr Nolan.
你以为他们会让这件事就这么过去了吗
Do you think for one moment they're gonna let this thing just blow over?
学校跨台就因为这种事 他们要找个替罪羊
Schools go down because of things like this. They need a scapegoat.
出什么事了 伙计们
What's going on, guys?
你去告密了 是不是 卡梅伦
You finked, didn't you, Cameron?
告密 我不知道你都在说什么
"Finked"? I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
我在说你把俱乐部的事都告诉了诺兰
You told Nolan everything about the club is what I'm talking about.
可能你没听说过 多尔顿
Look, in case you hadn't heard, Dalton, there's something...
学校有条信誉准则 知道吗
called an honour code at this school, all right?
如果老师问你个问题 你得说实话 不然就得开除
If a teacher asks you a question, you tell the truth or you're expelled.
- 你...  - 查理
- You...  - Charlie!
他是个叛徒 他脱不了干系
He's a rat! He's in it up to his eyes,
所以就去告密 想救自己
so he ratted to save himself!
别动他 查理 不然你就被开除了
Don't touch him, Charlie. You do and you're out.
我已经开除了
I'm out anyway!
- 你怎么知道 还不一定  - 他说得对 查理
- You don't know that. Not yet!  - He's right there, Charlie.
如果你们聪明点儿 你们会照我的做跟他们合作
And if you guys are smart, you will do exactly what I did and cooperate.
他们并不想追究我们 我们是受害者
They're not after us. We're the victims.
我们和尼尔
Us and Neil.
这是什么意思 他们在追究谁
What's that mean? Who are they after?
当然是基丁老师 船长本人
Why, Mr Keating, of course. The "Captain" himself!
你们也并不认为他没有责任 对不对
You guys didn't really think he could avoid responsibility, did you?
基丁老师对尼尔的死有责任 他们是这么说的
Mr Keating responsible for Neil? Is that what they're saying?
那你以为还有谁 笨蛋 校董会 佩里先生
Well, who else do you think, dumb ass? The administration? Mr Perry?
是基丁把我们灌输成这样的 对不对
Mr Keating put us up to all this crap, didn't he?
如果不是他 尼尔还...
If it wasn't for Mr Keating, Neil would be...
舒舒服服地呆在屋里学化学
cozied up in his room right now, studying his chemistry...
- 梦想成为一个医生  - 不是这样的 卡梅伦
- and dreaming of being called "Doctor"!  - That is not true, Cameron!
这你知道 他没灌输我们什么
You know that! He didn't put us up to anything.
- 是尼尔自己喜欢演戏  - 你爱怎么想怎么想吧
- Neil loved acting.  - Believe what you want,
反正我说基丁有责任
but I say let Keating fry.
干嘛毁了我们自己呢
I mean, why ruin our lives?
你已经被学校开除了 纽旺达
You just signed your expulsion papers, Nuwanda.
如果你们其他人够聪明 就照我的做
And if the rest of you are smart, you'll do exactly what I did!
反正他们也全知道了
They know everything anyway.
你们救不了基丁
You can't save Keating,
但可以救你们自己
but you can save yourselves.
诺克斯・奥弗斯特里特
Knox Overstreet.
- 米克斯  - 走开 我要学习
- Meeks.  - Go away. I have to study.
纽旺达怎么了
What happened to Nuwanda?
被开除了
Expelled.
你跟他们说了什么
What'd you tell 'em?
都是他们已经知道的东西
Nothing they didn't already know.
托德・安德森
Todd Anderson.
- 嗨 儿子  - 你好 宝贝
- Hello, son.  - Hello, darling.
妈妈
Mom.
请坐 安德森
Have a seat, Mr Anderson.
安德森 我想我们已经很清楚发生的事了
Mr Anderson, I think we've pretty well put together what's happened here.
你承认你是死亡诗人俱乐部的一员吗
You do admit to being a part of this Dead Poets Society?
快回答 托德
Answer him, Todd.
是的
Yes, sir.
我这儿有一份你们聚会的详细情况
I have here a detailed description of what occurred at your meetings.
里面谈到你们的老师 基丁
It describes how your teacher, Mr Keating,
是怎么鼓励你们组织这个俱乐部
encouraged you boys to organize this club...
并把它作为一个
and to use it as a source of inspiration
煽动鲁莽任性行为的中心
for reckless and self-indulgent behaviour.
还谈到基丁老师是如何在课内课外
It describes how Mr Keating, both in and out of the classroom,
鼓动尼尔・佩里去演戏
encouraged Neil Perry to follow his obsession with acting...
尽管他一直都知道这是违背他父母的明确规定的
when he knew all along it was against the explicit orders of Neil's parents.
正是基丁老师滥用了他作为一个老师的影响力
It was Mr Keating's blatant abuse of his position as teacher...
才导致了尼尔的死亡
that led directly to Neil Perry's death.
仔细看一下这份报告 托德
Read that document carefully, Todd.
好好看看
Very carefully.
如果没什么要补充的 签个字吧
If you've nothing to add or amend, sign it.
基丁老师会怎么样
What's gonna happen to Mr Keating?
我已经受够了 快签字 托德
I've had enough. Sign the paper, Todd!
草叫格莱蒙或者赫伯
Grass is gramen or herba.
石头叫莱皮斯
Lapis is stone.
一幢楼叫埃迪菲西恩
The entire building is aedificium.
坐
Sit.
这学期的英语课由我来上完
I'll be teaching this class through exams.
假期的时候再找一个正式的英语老师
We'll find a permanent English teacher during the break.
谁能告诉我普里查特的课本学到哪儿了
Who will tell me where you are in the Pritchard textbook?
安德森
Mr Anderson?
- 呃 学到...  - 我听不清 安德森
- Uh, in the, in the Prit...  - I can't hear you, Mr Anderson.
普里查特的课本...
In the, in the, in the Pritchard...
你告诉我吧 卡梅伦
Kindly inform me, Mr Cameron.
很多地方都跳过去了 老师
We skipped around a lot, sir.
学了浪漫主义诗人还有内战后文学的几章
We covered the romantics and some of the chapters on post-Civil War literature.
- 现实主义作家呢  - 差不多全跳过去了
- What about the realists?  - We skipped most of that, sir.
好吧 那我们从头学起
All right, then, we'll start over.
什么是诗歌
What is poetry?
进来
Come!
对不起
Excuse me.
我来拿我的东西
I came for my personals.
要不要我下课再来
Should I come back after class?
现在就拿吧 基丁先生
Get them now, Mr Keating.
各位 翻到前言第二十一页
Gentlemen, turn to page 21 of the introduction.
卡梅伦
Mr Cameron,
把普里查特博士...
read aloud the excellent essay by Dr Pritchard...
这篇题为"诗歌鉴赏"的文章念一遍
on "Understanding Poetry."
这一页被撕掉了 老师
That page has been ripped out, sir.
那就借一下别人的
Well, borrow somebody else's book.
他们全都撕了 老师
They're all ripped out, sir.
你是什么意思 全都撕了
What do you mean, "They're all ripped out"?
- 老师 我们...  - 没关系
- Sir, we... Ac...  - Never mind.
念吧
Read.
"诗歌鉴赏" 作者J・埃文斯・普里查特博士
'Understanding Poetry' by DrJ. Evans Pritchard, Ph.D.
"要完全理解诗歌 我们首先必须了解..."
"To fully understand poetry, we must first be fluent...
它的格调 韵律和修辞手法"
"with its metre, rhyme and figures of speech.
"然后提两个问题 第一"
"Then ask two questions. One:
"诗歌的主题是如何艺术地实现的"
"How artfully has the objective of the poem been rendered?
"第二..."
"And, two:
"该主题的重要性如何"
"How important is that objective?
"第一个问题解决的是诗歌的艺术性"
"Question one rates the poem's perfection.
"第二个问题回答的是它的重要性"
"Question two rates its importance.
"一旦弄清这两个问题"
'And once these questions have been answered,
"判断该诗的优劣也就不是个太难的问题了"
"determining a poem's greatness becomes a relatively simple matter.
"如果把诗歌艺术性的得分画在图表的横轴上
If the poem's score for perfection is plotted
把它的重要性..."
on the horizontal of a graph..."
基丁老师 是他们逼我们签字
Mr Keating! They made everybody sign it.
安静 安德森
Quiet, Mr Anderson!
- 请你相信我 是真的  - 我相信你 托德
- You've got to believe me. It's true.  - I do believe you, Todd.
- 走吧 基丁  - 这不是他的错
- Leave, Mr Keating.  - But it wasn't his fault!
坐下 安德森 你再说话或者有谁敢说话...
Sit down, Mr Anderson! One more outburst from you or anyone else,
就开除谁
and you're out of this school!
走吧 基丁
Leave, Mr Keating.
我叫你走 基丁先生
I said, "Leave, Mr Keating."
- 哦 船长 我的船长  - 坐下 安德森
- O Captain, my Captain.  - Sit down, Mr Anderson.
听见没有 坐下
Do you hear me? Sit down!
坐下
Sit down!
最后警告你一次 安德森
This is your final warning, Anderson.
大胆 听见没有
How dare you. Do you hear me?
哦 船长 我的船长
O Captain, my Captain.
奥弗斯特里特 我警告你
Mr Overstreet, I warn you!
坐下
Sit down!
坐下 全都坐下 我叫你们坐下
Sit down! All of you! I want you seated!
坐下 走吧 基丁先生
Sit down! Leave, Mr Keating.
全都坐下 快坐下
All of you, down! I want you seated!
没听见吗
Do you hear me?
坐下
Sit down!
谢谢 孩子们
Thank you, boys.
谢谢你们
Thank you.